<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Cambridge jests, or, Witty alarums for melancholy spirits by a lover of ha, ha, he.</title>
            <author>Lover of ha, ha, he.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1674</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 190 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 82 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A32424</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing C332</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R7388</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">11976395</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 11976395</idno>
            <idno type="VID">51789</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A32424)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 51789)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 58:2)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Cambridge jests, or, Witty alarums for melancholy spirits by a lover of ha, ha, he.</title>
                  <author>Lover of ha, ha, he.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[4], 152, [4] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Samuel Lowndes, and are to be sold at his shop ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1674.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Advertisements: ([4] p.) at end.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>English wit and humor.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-12</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-12</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="license">
            <pb facs="tcp:51789:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>Licenſed Octob. 9. 1673.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Roger L'Eſtrange.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:51789:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>Cambridge JESTS, OR WITTY ALARUMS FOR <hi>Melancholy Spirits.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>By a Lover of</hi> Ha, Ha, He.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>Samuel Lowndes,</hi> and are to be ſold at his Shop over againſt <hi>Exeter-Houſe</hi> in the <hi>Strand.</hi> MDCLXXIV.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:51789:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:51789:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>
               <hi>CAMBRIDGE</hi> JESTS.</head>
            <div n="1" type="jest">
               <head>1.</head>
               <p>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">A</seg> Young Lady having of a long time had a deſire to have her Picture drawn by an excel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lent Limner, ſent for him, and told him, That for as much as ſhe had heard he was an excellent Artiſt, ſhe deſired he would draw her to the life, as ſhe was, a Maid, and exact<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly of the ſame ſtature. The Painter ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving uſed the utmoſt of his Art to reſemble her Features to the life, brought home the Piece; in the which ſhe could find no fault, except that he had drawn her a lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle leſs than ſhe was. <hi>Oh Madam,</hi> ſaid
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:51789:3"/>
he, <hi>Poſterity would never believe my Draught, had I made you any taller; for 'tis very rare in this Age, to find a Maid ſo bigg.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="2" type="jest">
               <head>2.</head>
               <p>'Twas in the Rebellious Times of <hi>Oli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver,</hi> that a Phanatical Souldier came drunk into <hi>Kings Colledge</hi> Chappel at <hi>Cambridge</hi> and going to the place where Prayers uſed to be read, he began to rail againſt the King, the Biſhops, and particularly the two Univerſities, calling them the two Eyes of the Devil; adding moreover, that as his party had ruined the Walls of one, meaning that of <hi>Oxford,</hi> ſo they would deface the other of <hi>Cambridge. Nay then,</hi> replied a Scholar, <hi>I perceive</hi> Cambridge <hi>will be defaced when the Devil is blind,</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="3" type="jest">
               <head>3.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman that had occaſion to riſe early the next Morning, bid his Footman wake him at ſix a Clock, the little lad o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver vigilant, awaked at four, and came and pulled his Maſter; <hi>Well how now,</hi> ſaid his Maſter, <hi>what is it a clock? Four,</hi> repli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed the youth; <hi>And why Sirrah,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>have you awaked me ſo ſoon? Oh Sir,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>I came to tell you that you had two hours more to ſleep.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="4" type="jest">
               <pb n="3" facs="tcp:51789:3"/>
               <head>4.</head>
               <p>A Student in the Univerſity, ſent one day to his Fellow Collegian, deſiring to bor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>row ſuch a certain Book, the other unwil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling to lend it, ſent back word, <hi>That he had reſolved never to let that Book go out of his Chamber, but if he pleaſed he might come and read as long as he would;</hi> not long after having himſelf occaſion for a pair of Bellows, he ſent to borrow them of the other, to whom he had formerly denied his Book; but received this witty denial, for ſaid the other to the Meſſenger, <hi>I uſe not to lend out my Bellows, but if he pleaſe to come here, he may blow as long as he will.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="5" type="jest">
               <head>5.</head>
               <p>Some Gentlemen meeting their Friend that was in mourning for his Mother, up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on a Horſe whoſe Saddle was of Green Velvet, began to laugh at him for the diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>agreeableneſs of his Mourning Habit with the Green Saddle. <hi>Why Gentlemen,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>you know I mourn for my Mother, and therefore wear theſe Black Garments; but the Maere that brought forth my Horſe is yet living, and till ſhe die, there is no reaſon that he ſhould mourn.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="6" type="jest">
               <pb n="4" facs="tcp:51789:4"/>
               <head>6.</head>
               <p>An old Miſer in <hi>France,</hi> that grudg'd his Servants their Victuals, cauſing them to mingle three times as much Water with their Wine, ſeeing one of his ſervants feed heartily, <hi>What,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>will your Grin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders never be at reſt? How can they,</hi> reply'd the Servant, <hi>as long as they have ſo much Water?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="7" type="jest">
               <head>7.</head>
               <p>A Biſhop riſing up in Arms againſt his Prince, was overthrown and taken as he was clad in his Armour, and by the Kings Commands clapt up. The Pope hearing of it, complained to the King of breach of the Church Priviledges, that one of her Sons was impriſoned: Hereupon the King ſends back the Meſſenger with the Biſhops Armour, deſiring the Pope to ſend him word, <hi>Whether thoſe were the Garments of any of his Sons?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="8" type="jest">
               <head>8.</head>
               <p>Pope <hi>Julius</hi> the Third when he was made Pope, gave his Hat unto a young Favorite of his, with great ſcandal, whereupon a Cardinal that uſed to be free with him, ſaid, <hi>What did your Holineſs ſee in that young man, to make him Cardinal?
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:51789:4"/>
Julius</hi> anſwered, <hi>What did you ſee in me to make me Pope?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="9" type="jest">
               <head>9.</head>
               <p>A notorious Rogue being brought to the Bar, and knowing his Caſe to be de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſperate, cry'd out aloud, <hi>I charge you in the Kings name to ſeize and take away that man</hi> (meaning the Judge) <hi>in the red Gown, for I go in danger of my life becauſe of him.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="10" type="jest">
               <head>10.</head>
               <p>Amongſt ſome Women that were chat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting of their Husbands, <hi>Truly,</hi> ſaid one, <hi>my Husband is the liquoriſheſt Man in the World, for I had a little Pot of Honey ſent me by a Coſin out of</hi> Hampſhire, <hi>and I can no ſooner turn my Breech but his Noſe is in it.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="11" type="jest">
               <head>11.</head>
               <p>Another good Wife having drunke a little too largely in the Morning, fell aſleep in the Church, and began to ſnore ſo loud that her next Neighbour jogged her. <hi>Oh pray give the Cup to my Goſſip there,</hi> ſaid ſhe, <hi>for I cannot drink one drop more.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="12" type="jest">
               <head>12.</head>
               <p>A Countrey Fellow being ſet upon by a Maſtiff, kill'd him with his Pitchfork, the owner of the Dog demanded ſatisfaction,
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:51789:5"/>
and brought him before the Juſtice: But ſtill the Clown pleaded he did it in his own defence. <hi>Nevertheleſs you ought,</hi> ſaid the Juſtice, <hi>to have ſtruck him with the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther end of your Staffe. Truly ſo I would,</hi> ſaid the Peaſant, <hi>had he run at me with his Tail.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="13" type="jest">
               <head>13.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Francis</hi> the Firſt of <hi>France,</hi> often uſed for his pleaſure to go diſguiſed; walking thus one day in the company of the Cardi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nal of <hi>Bourbon,</hi> he met with a Peaſant with a new pair of Shoes upon his Arm; ſo he called to him, and ſaid, <hi>What did they coſt thee?</hi> the Peaſant ſaid, <hi>Gueſs;</hi> the King ſaid, <hi>I think ſome five Sols;</hi> ſaid the Pea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſant. <hi>You have lied but one Carlois. What Villain,</hi> ſaid the Cardinal, <hi>thou art dead; it is the King:</hi> To which the Peaſant reply'd, <hi>The Devil take him, of me, or you that knew ſo much.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="14" type="jest">
               <head>14.</head>
               <p>One having occaſion to riſe early, bid his Man look out and ſee if it were day; the man reply'd, <hi>It was dark; Why then Fool,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>'tis no wonder if thou canſt not ſee, take a Candle and hold out of the Window.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="15" type="jest">
               <pb n="7" facs="tcp:51789:5"/>
               <head>15.</head>
               <p>A Souldier quartering in <hi>New-Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ket,</hi> often obſerved a young Countrey Wench that ſold Pigs every Market day; whereupon he went to her one day, and deſired to ſee ſome Pigs; having ſeen ſeve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral, he ſaid at laſt, <hi>He would have one that was alive,</hi> ſo ſhe ſhewed him one that ſhe had in a Bag. <hi>Well, Sweet heart,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>I live hard by and muſt go ſhew the Pig to my Captain, if he like it, you ſhall have three ſhillings for it, in the mean time I will leave the price with you.</hi> Thus having got the Pig tied up in the Bag, he went to his Lodging, and put a Dog into the Bag in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtead of it, and returning quickly to the Damoſel, ſaid, <hi>Truly his Captain did not like the Pig;</hi> and therefore ſhe took the Bag without looking into it, and gave him his Money. Not long after came a French Monſieur in haſte to buy a Pig, but not liking thoſe that were dead, would have a live one. <hi>Sir,</hi> ſaid ſhe, <hi>I have one of the ſame bigneſs alive, the price is ſo much. Well, here is your money,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>but how ſhall I carry it? Why for a groat you ſhall have Poke and all. Poke, what is d'at?</hi> ſaid the Frenchman. <hi>'Tis a Bag Sir,</hi> ſaid ſhe, <hi>that it is tied up in. Oh de Bag, is dat de
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:51789:6"/>
Poke? well here is a groat.</hi> Thus away he goes with his Bargain home, but when he comes to look in the Poke, <hi>O de Dia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble;</hi> ſays he, <hi>is dis de Pig? de Dible take me, if I do buy de Pig in de Poke agin.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="16" type="jest">
               <head>16.</head>
               <p>A Taylor that was ever accuſtomed to ſteal ſome of the Cloth his Cuſtomer brought, when he came one day to make himſelf a Suit, ſtole half a yard; his Wife perceiving it, asked the reaſon; <hi>Oh,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>'tis to keep my hands in uſe, leaſt at any time I ſhould forget it.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="17" type="jest">
               <head>17.</head>
               <p>A Scholar that fancy'd himſelf to ſing well, notwithſtanding he had a very hoarſe voice; having often obſerved that a poor woman was uſed to cry when ſhe heard him ſing, asked her at laſt the reaſon. <hi>Truly Sir,</hi> ſaid ſhe, <hi>when through poverty I had ſold all my goods, and had nothing left but a poor Aſs, at laſt I loſt my Aſs, and I ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver hear you ſing, but you put me in mind of it.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="18" type="jest">
               <head>18.</head>
               <p>A Cook leaving his Maſter, who was very miſerable and ſparing in his Diet; when his Maſter asked him the reaſon, <hi>Truly Sir,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>I am afraid that if I
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:51789:6"/>
ſtay here long, I ſhould forget my Trade.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="19" type="jest">
               <head>19.</head>
               <p>One ſeeing a bare-legg'd Fellow run on an errand, ſaid, <hi>Do you hear friend, when thoſe Stockings are worn out, I will give you a new pair. I thank you Sir,</hi> replied the other, <hi>theſe Stockings have laſted me a great while; I have alſo a pair of Breeches of the ſame Stuffe, that never had but one hole in them, and that's at your ſervice too.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="20" type="jest">
               <head>20.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman paſſing by, a poor man asked alms of him; whereupon the Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tleman asked him what he lived upon? <hi>Sir,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>I can make no anſwer to that; but had you asked me what I die of? I ſhould have told you of hunger.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="21" type="jest">
               <head>21.</head>
               <p>A drunken Hector being brought be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore a Juſtice of Peace upon the account of Swearing, was commanded to depoſite his Fine, which was two ſhillings: there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon plucking out a Half-Crown, ſaid, <hi>Pray what ſhould I have paid had I curſed?</hi> the Juſtice told him <hi>Six pence: Then,</hi> quoth he, <hi>a pox take you all for a company of Knaves and Fools, and there's Half a Crown for you; I will never ſtand changing of Money.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="22" type="jest">
               <pb n="10" facs="tcp:51789:7"/>
               <head>22.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman meeting the Kings Jeſter, asked, <hi>What news? Why Sir,</hi> reply'd he, <hi>There are forty thouſand men riſen to day. I pray to what end,</hi> ſaid the other, <hi>and what do they intend? Why to go to bed again at night,</hi> ſaid he.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="23" type="jest">
               <head>23.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman playing a Game at Tables in a Chamber in <hi>Fleet-ſtreet,</hi> four ſtories high, had ſo ordered his Game, that no chance of the Dice could loſe it but one; yet it ſo happen'd that that chance came; whereupon he grew ſo paſſionate, that bringing down the Tables into the Street, he made a ſtop, and asking the next Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tleman that came if he underſtood the Game, the Gentleman ſaid he did; <hi>Then pray Sir,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>what do you think could loſe me the Game?</hi> then pauſing a little, <hi>I think there's nothing but ſuch a chance. Why then,</hi> ſaid the paſſionate Gameſter, <hi>God dam me, if I have not thrown it.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="23" type="jest">
               <head>23.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>One asked,</hi> Why men ſooner gave to poor people that begged, than to Scholars? 'Tis, <hi>ſaid one,</hi> becauſe they think they may ſooner come to be poor, than to be Scho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lars.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="24" type="jest">
               <pb n="11" facs="tcp:51789:7"/>
               <head>24.</head>
               <p>A Courtier having begg'd a rich Land<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Fool of the King, made him wait up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on him; ſo the Fool coming one day with his Maſter to a Gentlemans Houſe, where the Picture of a Fool was wrought in a rich Suit of Arras Hangings, cut out the Fool with his knife; and being accuſed for it, <hi>You have more reaſon,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>to commend, and give me thanks for it; for had my Maſter ſeen the Picture of a Fool in your Hangings, he would have begg'd them of the King.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="25" type="jest">
               <head>25.</head>
               <p>A Countreyman coming to <hi>Paris</hi> with his Aſs loaded, the Beaſt ſtuck in a d<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>rty place of the Road; wherefore the Peaſant ſtruck him with a ſtick to make him riſe: till at laſt a Courtier paſſing by, ſaid, <hi>How now Villain, art thou not aſhamed to abuſe thy Beaſt ſo? If thou ſtrikeſt him a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gain, I will give thee a hundred blows with the ſame Cudgel.</hi> The poor man ignorant what to do, pull'd off his Hat till the Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tleman was paſt, and then began to beat his Beaſt worſe than before; ſaying, <hi>How now mine Aſs, who would have thought that thou hadſt had friends at Court?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="26" type="jest">
               <pb n="12" facs="tcp:51789:8"/>
               <head>26.</head>
               <p>A French Peaſant paſſing by a Ditch with his Cart full of Onions, the Cart o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verturned, and the Onions fell into the Water; then ſeeing there was no remedy, <hi>Morebleau,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>here wants nothing but ſalt to make good pottage.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="27" type="jest">
               <head>27.</head>
               <p>A Stranger being much neceſſitated, as he walked into the City, to do that no one could do for him; and being in a place far from any of his acquaintances, and void of convenience for that purpoſe, went into an Upholſters Shop, and asked the Man to ſhew him a Cloſe-Stool, which being done, he asked if he had no better; <hi>Yes Sir, we have,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>of all coloured Velvet: Go then,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>and fetch two or three;</hi> in the mean time he let down his Breeches and ſate down; the Upholſterer ſeeing him in that poſture, asked him, <hi>What he did? I am trying it,</hi> ſaid he, and pulling up his Breeches, <hi>I will have none of them, they are all too low.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="28" type="jest">
               <head>28.</head>
               <p>An Apprentice of <hi>London</hi> being brought before the Chamberlain by his Maſter, for the ſin of incontinency, even with his own Miſtriſs; the Chamberlain thereupon gave
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:51789:8"/>
him many Chriſtian Exhortations, and at laſt mentioned and preſs'd the Chaſtity of <hi>Joſeph,</hi> when his Miſtriſs tempted him with the like crime of incontinency. <hi>I Sir,</hi> ſaid the Apprentice, <hi>but if</hi> Joſeph's <hi>Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtriſs had been as handſome as mine is, he could not have forborn.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="29" type="jest">
               <head>29.</head>
               <p>It happen'd in <hi>Chancery,</hi> when the Council of the Parties ſet forth the boun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dary of the Land in queſtion, by the Plot, and the Council of one part, ſaid, <hi>We lie on this ſide, my Lrod;</hi> and the Council of the other part, ſaid, <hi>We lie on this ſide;</hi> the Lord Chancellor ſtood up and ſaid, <hi>If you lie on both ſides, whom will you have me believe?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="30" type="jest">
               <head>30.</head>
               <p>It happen'd that an old and a young Gentleman courted a young Lady, and both one day met at her Houſe together; the young one being much troubled at the ſight of his Rival, ſaid mocking, <hi>Pray Sir, how old are you?</hi> To which the old man anſwered, <hi>'Twere hard for me to tell you exactly my age, becauſe I never reckoned it, but I am very certain that an Aſs of twenty is older than a man of forty.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="31" type="jest">
               <pb n="14" facs="tcp:51789:9"/>
               <head>31.</head>
               <p>A young Horſeman being mounted, was carried away by his Horſe, his Friends fearing the Horſe would throw him, call'd to him to ſtay him; <hi>How ſhould I ſtay him,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>ſeeing I have no ſpurs?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="32" type="jest">
               <head>32.</head>
               <p>A prudent Gentleman in the beginning of the Rebellious Times, as he lay on his Death-bed, was asked how he would be buried? he anſwered, <hi>With my face down<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward, for within a while this</hi> England <hi>will be turned upſide down, and then I ſhall lie right.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="33" type="jest">
               <head>33.</head>
               <p>Sir <hi>Nicholas Bacon</hi> being appointed Judge for the Northern Circuit, was by a Malefactor mightily importuned to ſave his life; but when nothing he could ſay did avail, he deſired his mercy on the ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>count of kindred: <hi>Pretheee,</hi> ſaid my Lord Judge, <hi>how comes that in? Why, if it pleaſe you, my Lord, your name is</hi> Bacon, <hi>and mine is</hi> Hog, <hi>and thoſe two have ever been ſo near related, that they cannot be ſeparated. I but,</hi> replied Judge <hi>Bacon, you and I can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not be kindred, except you be hanged; for</hi> Hog <hi>is not</hi> Bacon, <hi>until it be hanged.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="34" type="jest">
               <pb n="15" facs="tcp:51789:9"/>
               <head>34.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>One ſeeing the Rump in Council,</hi> Oh ſtrange, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> what fine men be theſe, I could willingly work for ſuch as long as I live. What Trade are you pray? <hi>ſaid ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther;</hi> Why truly, <hi>replied he,</hi> I am a Cord-winder.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="35" type="jest">
               <head>35.</head>
               <p>Two coming to an Inn, they bid the Hoſtler give their Horſes ſome Oats; pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſently one going down, ſaw the Hoſtler robbing the Horſes, for which chiding him, he returned to his Companion, that had truſted too much upon the Hoſtlers fi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>delity: <hi>What,</hi> ſaid his Companion, <hi>have the Horſes dined already? Yes, I believe yours hath,</hi> replied he, <hi>for as I went down juſt now, I ſaw the Hoſtler taking away.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="36" type="jest">
               <head>36</head>
               <p>A Gentleman paſſing by with a very ſhort Cloak, his Friend ſaid to him, <hi>Sir, your Cloak is too ſhort; You'r miſtaken,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>'twill be long enough before I get an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>other.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="37" type="jest">
               <head>37.</head>
               <p>A Countreyman newly come up to <hi>London,</hi> to ſell ſome Apples, a Collier called after him to buy ſome, the poor
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:51789:10"/>
man, ſeeing the Colliar, on a ſudden ſet down his Basket, and ran away crying, <hi>I defie the Devil, I defie thee, take them all.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="38" type="jest">
               <head>38.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman in the Rebellious Times, as he was in his Chamber amongſt his Friends making merry, there came a Muſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ket Bullet through the Window, and glancing againſt a Marble Chimney-piece, hit him on the head without farther da<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mage, then fell at his feet, the Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man turning the flatted Bullet with his fingers, <hi>Gentlemen,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>thoſe that had a mind to flatter me, were wont to ſay that I had a good Head-piece in my younger days; but if I do not flatter my ſelf, I think I have a good Head-piece in my old age, for it is Musket proof.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="39" type="jest">
               <head>39.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman having loſt his ſight, his Friends often asked how he could be ſo merry; <hi>Why, before,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>I uſed to go alone, but now I have alwayes com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="40" type="jest">
               <head>40.</head>
               <p>Two Innkeepers falling out one day who ſhould entertain a Lord and his Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinue, that was to paſs that way; he that
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:51789:10"/>
was leſs happy in the occaſion, ſtood at his Door, ſaying to thoſe that paſſed by, <hi>See that envious man,</hi> pointing to the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, <hi>ho is willing that every thing he hath, ſhould eat me up; for example, his Cat this morning eat me two pound of Butter.</hi> The other to juſtifie himſelf, brought out a pair of Scales in the middle of the Street, weighed his Cat, and ſaid, <hi>See good peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple, what an envious and lying man this is, the Cat doth not weigh a pound and an half with all that is in her, and yet he ſaith ſhe hath eat this morning two pound of his Butter.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="41" type="jest">
               <head>41.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman, none of the wiſeſt, ſee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing a Houſe very ſtately built, told the Porter it was much of the Italian Mode, and asked whether it were made in <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land?</hi> the Porter ſeeing his ſimplicity, ſaid, <hi>No Sir, it was made in</hi> Venice, <hi>and brought hither by two Merchants.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="42" type="jest">
               <head>42.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman complaining to his Friend that he had loſt an honeſt woman, foraſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>much as his Wife was dead. <hi>Nay, had ſhe been honeſt,</hi> ſaid the other, <hi>ſhe would never have left you.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="43" type="jest">
               <pb n="18" facs="tcp:51789:11"/>
               <head>43.</head>
               <p>A Lord, as he was travelling on the Road, his Coach-horſes tired, and for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ced him to take up Inn, where being impa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tient of ſtaying, his Fool ſaid to him, <hi>Let us go, if it pleaſe your Lordſhip, before in the Coach, and the Horſes may come after.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="44" type="jest">
               <head>44.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Pace</hi> the bitter Fool, was not ſuffered to come at the Queen, becauſe of his bit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter humor, yet at laſt ſome preſſed the Queen that he ſhould come to her, under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taking for him that he ſhould keep com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paſs; ſo he was brought to her, and the Queen ſaid, <hi>Come on</hi> Pace, <hi>now we ſhall hear of our faults.</hi> Saith <hi>Pace, I do not uſe to talk of that, which all the Town talks of.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="45" type="jest">
               <head>45.</head>
               <p>One rode furiouſly among ſome Qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kers that ſtood in a yard, hearing the Spea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ker from the top of the Barn, and being rebuked by a Brother, <hi>Why ſhould not my Horſe,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>have to do here at the meet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, as well as the reſt of the Aſſes.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="46" type="jest">
               <head>46.</head>
               <p>Some merry Companions having been at an Ordinary all day, when by much drink they began to be mad, began at laſt
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:51789:11"/>
to jeer one another concerning their Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtriſſes, whereat one ſtruck the other a box in the ear, and all expected ſome bloody event; but the injur'd perſon de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded what the other meant, whether he were in jeſt or in earneſt; <hi>In earneſt,</hi> ſaid the other, whoſe Collar had carried him beyond the bounds of Friendſhip. The other more conſiderate and loath to quarrel with his Friend, <hi>'Tis well you are,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>for I like not ſuch jeſting.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="47" type="jest">
               <head>47.</head>
               <p>Several perſons of ſeveral Callings, being invited to a Feaſt, it happen'd that amongſt the reſt, there came an old Grammarian, not altogether arrayed af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter the mode, nor cloathed ſo well, as many other young Gallants that were there; this gave occaſion when the Wine had made every man's tongue free to ſpeak his mind, that a young Spark, to put a jeſt upon the old Grammarian, ſaid, <hi>Pray Sir, ſince I know you to be well skill'd in Genealogy, who was the Father of</hi> Peleus? to which he anſwered, <hi>Tell me firſt if you can, who was yours?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="48" type="jest">
               <head>48.</head>
               <p>In the time of Peace, when the Gown onely found employment, and Arms, as
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:51789:12"/>
uſeleſs, were laid aſide, a ſtout Souldier that had formerly done his Prince great ſervice, but was forgotten, finding it a difficult thing to be admitted to the Kings preſence, whereby he might make him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf known to him, ſtuck feathers in his hair, noſe, and ears, and danced about the Court in a moſt antick faſhion, till at laſt the ſtrangeneſs of the ſight, brought the King himſelf to be Spectator: Then this Mimick throwing off this diſguiſe, <hi>Sir,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>I thus arrive at your Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſties notice in the faſhion of a Fool, but can do you ſervice in the place of a wiſe man.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="49" type="jest">
               <head>49.</head>
               <p>An old Knight coming to Court, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>queſted a favour of the King, but recei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved a Denial of his Petition: wherefore knowing that his age was great, and his hairs grey, and thinking they were the cauſe why he did not ſucceed; he colour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed his Beard black, and put on a Peruque, and like a young man came again, and petitioned the King concerning the ſame buſineſs; his Majeſty perceiving the de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceit, ſaid to him, <hi>I would be very glad to gratifie you in your deſire, but 'tis not long ſince I deny'd it to your Father, and 'twere unjuſt to grant the Son what I deny'd him.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="50" type="jest">
               <pb n="21" facs="tcp:51789:12"/>
               <head>50.</head>
               <p>In the flouriſhing time of <hi>Greece,</hi> when young <hi>Alexander</hi> made the World ſhake, and the War began to be waged againſt the Perſian Monarchy, the timerous Spies told one of <hi>Alexander's</hi> Captains, That the Enemies, beſide all their other Milita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Preparations, brought ſo many Arch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers againſt him, as would darken the sky, and exclude the light of the Sun; at which news nothing daunted, <hi>Tis good news for us,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>that are in a hot countrey; for we ſhall fight in the ſhade.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="51" type="jest">
               <head>51.</head>
               <p>In <hi>Naples</hi> a City of <hi>Italy,</hi> there hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pen'd in a great Siege it endured, that the Governour made a ſevere Order, <hi>That every man ſhould be put to death, that being above ſuch an age, did not wear a Sword;</hi> but not long after, as he was riding through the Street, to ſee how well his Order was put in execution, he eſpied a Gentleman without a Sword, and com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded him to be brought before him, then was the Order read, and he condem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned to die the death appointed, which was to be hanged on the next Sign Poſt. The Gentleman, after he had pleaded ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral things in his own behalf, but could
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:51789:13"/>
avail nothing; nevertheleſs deſired this favour, that he might not die ſo ignomi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niouſly, but that the next Gentleman that paſſed, might run him through with his Sword: the requeſt being reaſonable, was granted, and the execution prorogued till the next came. Now it happen'd that a young Gallant was coming from a Game<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Houſe that way, that having loſt all, ſo much as the blade of his Sword, which was good Merchandiſe at that time, did not dare, in regard of the ſevere Order, to go home, until a woodden one was fitted to the handle: This Gentleman was ſtopt, and the dying mans caſe laid open; but this ingenious perſon, knowing his own inſufficiency, <hi>What,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>muſt I be a common Executioner? Muſt I ſtain my hands in blood without paſſion? and be a re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>proach to all men?</hi> Nevertheleſs this argu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment availed nothing, and kill him he muſt: then putting off his Cloak, he be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gan a Prayer to this effect, <hi>Thou who ſeeſt all the tranſactions here below, judge I pray thee, and vindicate the cauſe of thoſe that ſuffer wrong; in eſpecial manner grant that if this man here ought not to die, this Sword may be turned into wood.</hi> Then drawing it forth, it appeared to be wood; wherefore
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:51789:13"/>
the dying Gentleman was releaſed imme<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diately with abundance of joy, and the Woodden Sword was carried with great ſolemnity, and hung up in the Cathedral Church, as a true link to the Chain of Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>piſh Miracles.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="52" type="jest">
               <head>52.</head>
               <p>In theſe late times every diſcourſe being of preparations of War, and proceedings againſt the Dutch, amongſt many other queſtions, one was ſo curious, as to ask one in the company why the Dutch were called Butter-boxes? <hi>Tis,</hi> replied the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther merrily, <hi>becauſe they are ſpread over the whole world.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="53" type="jest">
               <head>53.</head>
               <p>A Seaman being extreamly dry in the middle of the Fight, was drinking to a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nother out of a Bottle of Brandy, when at the inſtant a Bullet coming through a Port-hole, kill'd him as he was drinking; wherefore falling down dead, and the Bot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle breaking, <hi>A pox light on you,</hi> ſaid the other, <hi>for a Rogue, to ſpill all the Brandy.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="54" type="jest">
               <head>54.</head>
               <p>There were at <hi>Newberry</hi> ſome She An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nabaptiſts, that took upon them to have Revelations, and therein to ſee ſuch glo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rious things as could not be related nor
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:51789:14"/>
imagined by others; drawing by ſuch means many poor ſimple people to be of their Religion, in hopes of ſeeing the like glorious Viſions. One amongſt the reſt told the holy Brotherhood, that ſhe had a Revelation to be taken up into Heaven on ſuch a night, the reſt reſolving to take their ſolemn leave of her, at the time ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed, all went out with her into the Fields, to ſee her glorious Aſcenſion; the night happen'd to be a Moon-ſhiny night, and as they expected, when ſome Angel ſhould come to fetch her in a Fiery Cha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riot, a Cloud covers the face of the Moon, whereupon they began to cry, <hi>Behold he comes in the clouds;</hi> but immediately their hopes vaniſhed with the Cloud.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="55" type="jest">
               <head>55.</head>
               <p>Another Quaker, being Apprentice to a Tradeſman in the City of <hi>London,</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>came at laſt, after he had received the Documents of his Miſtriſs, ſo Phanatical, that he would give new names to all things in the Shop; for being a Habberdaſher of Small Ware, if any one came for a Shuttle-cock, he call'd it a Flying Cock; if for a Ruler, he call'd it a Meaſure of Righteouſneſs; if for Needles, thoſe he called the Camels impoſſibility; if for
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:51789:14"/>
Ribbons, thoſe he named the Devils Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lours; inſomuch that he rendred himſelf incapable of Trading. One day above the reſt, when his Maſter had invited many Gueſts to dinner, he went into the Room, and taking a Stool, carried it to the upper end of the Table, and ſate down thereon covered. His Maſter much aſtoniſhed at his new impudence, eſpecially before ſo much company, asked him the reaſon; <hi>Why,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>I am the Servant of the Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving God, and have more right to the crea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures than you.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="56" type="jest">
               <head>56.</head>
               <p>A Valiant Captain, that had loſt his Leg formerly in the Wars, was neverthe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs for his great prudence and courage, made Captain of a Ship, and being in the midſt of an Engagement, a Cannon Bul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>let took off his woodden ſupporter, ſo that he fell down; the Seamen, foraſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>much as few knew he had a woodden leg, call'd out for the Surgeon: <hi>The Surgeon, a pox on you all,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>a Carpenter, a Carpenter.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="57" type="jest">
               <head>57.</head>
               <p>A ſevere School-Maſter having one morning, whipt one of his Boys, ſaw him as ſoon as he came to his place, write
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:51789:15"/>
ſomething in his Table-book; wherefore commanding him to bring the Book, and looking therein, he ſaw that the Lad had writ down every time he had been whipt at School; wherefore commending him for ſo doing, as if the writing them down, ſhould put the faults freſh in his memory, and make him eſchew them; he gave him half a Crown to buy him a Common-place Book. The Youth bought a Common-place Book, and the next day brought it to School; his Maſter ſeeing it, called him out for his Leſſon, and notwithſtanding the Boy did very well, whipt him. <hi>Pray Sir,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>let me know my fault, for I perceive nothing in my ſelf worthy of this pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhment? O,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>if I do not take this courſe, you will never fill your Common-place Book.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="58" type="jest">
               <head>58.</head>
               <p>A Citizen of <hi>London</hi> going along the Streets very haſtily, came at laſt where a great ſtop was made by Carts, and other Gentlemen talking together, who knew him; one of them ſaid to him, ſeeing him in a paſſion that he could not paſs ſud<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>denly; <hi>Others, Sir, have paſt by, and there was room enough; but it may be your horns are wider than theirs.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="59" type="jest">
               <pb n="27" facs="tcp:51789:15"/>
               <head>59.</head>
               <p>A Valiant Captain, when ſome of his ti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merous companions, to hinder the joyning of the Battle, told him their enemies were three times as many as they. <hi>Are they ſo,</hi> ſaid he, no whit diſmayed, <hi>then I am ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry glad; for there are enough to be killed, e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nough to be taken priſoners, and enough to run away.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="60" type="jest">
               <head>60.</head>
               <p>One who had alwayes been very jocoſe in his life time, when he lay on his Death-bed, his chief Clerk came and deſired he would leave him a Legacy: <hi>Here,</hi> ſaid he, giving him a Key, in ſuch a Drawer, <hi>there is that will make thee drink;</hi> not many hours after he died, and the youth greedily o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pening the Box, found nought there but two red Herrings.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="61" type="jest">
               <head>61.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>A merry Gentleman riding on the Road, ſaw a Boy foul his Breeches:</hi> Why Sirrah, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> are you not aſhamed to make a fool in your Breeches. Alas Sir, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> you make a worſe of your Doublet, to button up ſuch an Aſs in it.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="62" type="jest">
               <head>62.</head>
               <p>'Tis reported of a certain debaucht perſon, that he was wont very devoutly,
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:51789:16"/>
to ſay his prayers always in the morning, and then at his departure out of his Houſe, he would cry, <hi>Now Devil do thy worſt.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="63" type="jest">
               <head>63.</head>
               <p>Sir <hi>Roger Williams</hi> hearing a Spaniard fooliſhly brag of his Countrey Sallats, gave him this anſwer, <hi>You have indeed good Sauce in</hi> Spain, <hi>but we in</hi> England <hi>have dainty Beeves, Veals, and Muttons; and as God made Beaſts to live on Graſs, ſo he made Men to live on Beaſts.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="64" type="jest">
               <head>64.</head>
               <p>When the Trojans ſent Ambaſſadours to <hi>Tiberius,</hi> to condole the death of his Father <hi>Augustus,</hi> a long time after he was dead; the Emperour conſidering the unſeaſonableneſs of it, requited them ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cordingly, ſaying, <hi>And I am ſorry for your heavineſs, having loſt ſo valiant a Knight as</hi> Hector; <hi>who was ſlain above a thouſand years before.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="65" type="jest">
               <head>65.</head>
               <p>A certain Papiſt ſearching to know perfectly concerning the Maſs, found at the end of St. <hi>Paul</hi>'s Epiſtle, <hi>Miſſa eſt,</hi> and bragg'd he had found the Maſs in the Bi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble. Another reading <hi>John</hi> 1.4. <hi>Inve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nimus Meſſiam,</hi> made the ſame conclu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="66" type="jest">
               <pb n="29" facs="tcp:51789:16"/>
               <head>66.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>The Standers by comforting a natural that lay on his Death-bed, told him,</hi> That four proper fellows ſhould carry his Body to the Church; yea, <hi>quoth he,</hi> but I had by half rather go thither my ſelf.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="67" type="jest">
               <head>67.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Galateus,</hi> Duke of <hi>Millain,</hi> being told of a certain Lawyer, who by his quick and crafty wit, could draw a fair Glove on a foul hand, thereby multiplying Suits and wronging the innocent, ſent for him, and ſaid, <hi>Sir, I owe my Baker Five hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred pounds, and have no mind to pay him; will you undertake to defend me, and free me from the Debt?</hi> he anſwered, <hi>He would.</hi> The Duke therefore firſt reproved him ſharply for his deceit and wrong deal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, then cauſed him to be hanged.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="68" type="jest">
               <head>68.</head>
               <p>Two good Wives having now well warmed their knees by the fire, and their noſes over a pot and a toſt, fell into a hot diſpute concerning their Brewers: <hi>Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Damnable</hi> ſaid her Ale was the beſt in <hi>England,</hi> becauſe it was ſo; and <hi>Mother Louſe</hi> ſaid her Brewer brewed the beſt ſtale Beer in the world.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="69" type="jest">
               <pb n="30" facs="tcp:51789:17"/>
               <head>69.</head>
               <p>A Fool as he wandred by the River ſide, at laſt clim'd up an Oſier, and there ſeat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed himſelf; not long after one paſſing by that knew him, asked him, <hi>VVhat he did there? Onely gather a few Nuts,</hi> ſays he.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="70" type="jest">
               <head>70.</head>
               <p>A Boy going through the Streets with a Peck Loaf upon his head, where was a great concourſe of People, hit a Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man unawares with the corner of the Loaf over the face; <hi>VVhy how now you rude Raſcal,</hi> ſaid the Gentleman, <hi>cann't you ſee? Spare your breath,</hi> replied the youth, <hi>I am as well bred as your ſelf.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="71" type="jest">
               <head>71.</head>
               <p>A poor but witty lad, brought up to the Univerſity, and admitted in a Colledge, could not go to the price of a new pair of Shooes; but when his old ones were worn out at the toes, had them capt with Lea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther; whereupon his Companions began to jeer him for ſo doing: <hi>VVhy,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>muſt they not be capt, are they not fel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lows?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="72" type="jest">
               <head>72.</head>
               <p>A young Man having raiſed a Maids belly, and the bulk now evidently manife<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſting the fact, his Friends and Relations
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:51789:17"/>
came purpoſely together to reprove him; and every one had a ſaying at him, though in general every one ſaid, they wondered he ſhould do ſo and ſo. <hi>VVhy, what a wondring,</hi> ſaid the young man, <hi>do you make, that I ſhould get her with child, is not that uſual, therefore no cauſe of won<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der; but you might have wondered indeed, had ſhe got me with child.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="73" type="jest">
               <head>73.</head>
               <p>A Countrey Peaſant had often obſerv'd, that there appear'd not ſo many Stars in the Weſt as in the Eaſt; at which the Phy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>loſopher much concerned, often made it his buſineſs to walk out at night in the Fields; diligently obſerving the Weſt, to ſee if he could find out the reaſon: At laſt he ſaw a Meteor fall, by and by another, then two or three together: <hi>Nay then,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>I ſhall ceaſe to wonder that there be fewer Stars in the VVeſt than in the Eaſt, ſince ſo many fall every night.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="74" type="jest">
               <head>74.</head>
               <p>A Fool fearing to be beaten, went away privately, and hid himſelf behind ſome buſhes in the Garden; but when they be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gan to ſearch for him and could not find him, he peeps over the buſh, and cries, <hi>You don't ſee me, you cann't ſee me.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="75" type="jest">
               <pb n="32" facs="tcp:51789:18"/>
               <head>75.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>A Stranger paſſing through the Tem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple, had a Piſs-pot diſcharged upon his head; not long after he meets with a friend,</hi> Pray what place call you that? <hi>ſays he,</hi> 'Tis an Inn of Court, <hi>replied the other.</hi> And what do they do there? VVhy they ſtudy the Law. I believe rather, <hi>quoth he,</hi> they ſtudy Phyſick, they caſt ſo much water; and Rake<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hells they are I am ſure, for they throw the ſtools out of the windows too.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="76" type="jest">
               <head>76.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>A great Courtier ſeeing his Jeſter ſtum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble,</hi> VVhy how now, can you not ſtand? <hi>ſays he:</hi> Yes, <hi>replied he,</hi> I can, and ſtumble and riſe again too; but have a care, for if you fall, perhaps you may never riſe.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="77" type="jest">
               <head>77.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman paſſing through <hi>Cam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bridge</hi> on a foundred Horſe, ſaw a Scho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar of his acquaintance coming to meet him; ſtriving therefore to ſpare him the trouble, he whips his Horſe, crying, <hi>
                     <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>p Bacon.</hi> His Friend asketh him the reaſon why he call'd him <hi>Bacon? Becauſe,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>he is Very-lame.</hi> Now my Lord <hi>Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>con</hi>'s Title was <hi>Verulam.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="78" type="jest">
               <pb n="33" facs="tcp:51789:18"/>
               <head>78.</head>
               <p>Some merry Companions being at a Singing Club, amongſt many other Songs and Catches ſung at laſt that of <hi>New Oy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters, New Oyſters, New Oyſters, New, &amp;c.</hi> Whereupon one that ſtood by, laught to hear his Friend cry <hi>Oyſters.</hi> His Friend asked him how he would cry Oyſters? <hi>VVhy,</hi> replied he, <hi>I would cry, O yes, O yes, O yes,</hi> that is, <hi>O yes ter.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="79" type="jest">
               <head>79.</head>
               <p>King <hi>James</hi> having ſeen two Plays per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formed by the Scholars of both Univerſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, One of <hi>Cambridge,</hi> where one na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med <hi>Sleep,</hi> acted ſo well, that the King commanded him to ſtop, for fear he ſhould burſt with laughter. The other at <hi>Oxford,</hi> where one <hi>VVake</hi> acted ſo bad, that the King ſlept the beſt part of the Play. His Majeſty was pleaſed to ſay of them both, that as in <hi>Cambridge, Sleep</hi> made him wake, ſo in <hi>Oxford, VVake</hi> onely made him ſleep.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="80" type="jest">
               <head>80.</head>
               <p>A poor Boy knowing what eſteem Learning had in the World, begg'd under colour of being a poor Scholar; a Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man paſſing by, took pity on him, and ask<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed him in Latine what his Friends were?
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:51789:19"/>
whether they were alive? and the like; but ſtill he cries in the ſame tongue, <hi>Pray Sir pity a poor Scholar. VVhy you Raſcal,</hi> quoth the Gentleman, <hi>do you ſay you are a Scholar, and you underſtand not one word of Latine? 'Tis true,</hi> ſaid the Boy, <hi>I un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derſtand no Latine, and ſcarce can read En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gliſh; and that is the reaſon I deſire you to give ſomething to a very poor Scholar.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="81" type="jest">
               <head>81.</head>
               <p>VVere I a Prince, <hi>ſays a Countrey Boy;</hi> VVhy what then? <hi>anſwered hi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> Companion:</hi> Oh then I would eat my Bel<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ly full of Bacon, and ſwing upon a Gate a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> day long.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="82" type="jest">
               <head>82.</head>
               <p>Walking through the City in a grea<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> throng, a Perſon of Quality accidentall<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> loſt his Watch out of his Pocket, of whic<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> he complained to his Friend; <hi>Alas Sir<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                  </hi> ſaid the other, <hi>who can help it, time wi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap> away.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="83" type="jest">
               <head>83.</head>
               <p>A learned Gentlewoman put two Queſtions to a young Scholar; the firſt was, <hi>Why the Infinitive was next to the Optative?</hi> of which he ſaid, <hi>Becauſe w<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> never mak<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> an end of de<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſiring</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="35" facs="tcp:51789:19"/>Secondly, when he had anſwered her ſo well, ſhe bid him repeat to her a lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle of his Grammar; where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon he wittily began at <hi>Propria quae maribus.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="84" type="jest">
               <head>84.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>A witty Tavern Boy in the Spring time threw ſome dirt out aceidentally up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on a Bald-headed Gentleman, who being much incenſed thereat, demanded the reaſon;</hi> Becauſe Sir, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> ſince now the New year is begun, the Fields grow green, the Trees and Plants flouriſh, and all things look freſh and fair; I thought your Head was too backward, and wanted dunging.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="85" type="jest">
               <head>85.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>A learned Gentleman diſputing concer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning death, ſaid,</hi> It was all one to live or to die. Why do you not die then? <hi>ſaid ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther;</hi> Becauſe, <hi>replied he,</hi> it is all one.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="86" type="jest">
               <head>86.</head>
               <p>'Twas the humor of a witty perſon and a great Jeſter to a Nobleman, to cry in fair weather, and to laugh in foul. This ſeemed contrary to reaſon, and his Lord asked him wherefore he did ſo? <hi>Why when it is fair weather,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>I can expect nothing but that every minute foul
<pb n="36" facs="tcp:51789:20"/>
ſhould come; that makes me cry. In foul weather I alwayes expect that the sky ſhould clear, that makes me laugh.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="87" type="jest">
               <head>87.</head>
               <p>A vertuous Gentleman being asked by a Knave, what was Piety? <hi>What is that to you,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>meddle with thoſe things that concern you.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="88" type="jest">
               <head>88.</head>
               <p>A grave Citizen in <hi>London,</hi> though not ſo wiſe as he ſhould be, talking with ſome of his Neighbours, concerning his Shop he had then newly rebuilt after the fire; <hi>Truly,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>I think I have contrived in to the beſt advantage; for it hath the Morn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Sun all day long in it.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="89" type="jest">
               <head>89.</head>
               <p>'Twas at firſt, when the Faſhion of white Freeze came up amongſt the Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tlemen, eſpecially for Riding Suits, that a Wiſe-acre conſidering that it was then moſt in faſhion, a laſting and ſerviceable Garment, asked, <hi>If there were no black of that colour, for he had a great mind to have a Coat made of it?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="90" type="jest">
               <head>90.</head>
               <p>A proud Londoner travelling to <hi>Goat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>am,</hi> and meeting a poor fellow coming from thence, thinking to ſhew his wit,
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:51789:20"/>
ſaid, <hi>Well met Fool of</hi> Goatam, <hi>how far to the place of thy nativity? True it is,</hi> ſaid the poor man, <hi>my Countrey is a ſhame to me, but you proud</hi> Londoner <hi>are a ſhame to your Countrey.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="91" type="jest">
               <head>91.</head>
               <p>Two men meeting in the ſtreet and quarrelling, it came ſo far at laſt that one gave the other a kick in the breech. The people much admired the others patience, inviting him to revenge that injury: <hi>What,</hi> ſays he, <hi>if an Aſs kicks me, muſt I go to law with him.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="92" type="jest">
               <head>92.</head>
               <p>The day proving very windy, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in one was to perform his journey, who was ſcarce ever before farther than his Street, his friends diſſuaded him, ſaying, <hi>The wind would be very troubleſome to him. Oh, let me alone,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>I will ride out of the wind.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="93" type="jest">
               <head>93.</head>
               <p>One being demanded, Why learned men frequented rich mens Pallaces, but rich ſeldome viſited the learned? anſwer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, <hi>That the firſt knew what they want<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, the later did not.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="94" type="jest">
               <pb n="38" facs="tcp:51789:21"/>
               <head>94.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>One exclaiming againſt another that ran away in his debt,</hi> A Pox light on him, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> I am ſure I lent him Six and forty good ſhillings all in Half Crowns.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="95" type="jest">
               <head>95.</head>
               <p>An impudent Strumpet ſeeing a poor Countreyman receive Ten pounds, ſeiſed on him, and brought him before the Judge, ſwearing he would have raviſhed her, nay that he did; inſomuch that the poor man, who never had to do with her, notwithſtanding all his innocence, could not clear himſelf of the accuſation; and ſtill ſhe urged that he ought to marry her: ſo the buſineſs was put to a pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick Trial, where at laſt, I know not by what means, it was concluded that the man ſhould give her Ten pounds to clear the buſineſs. The poor man, after he had delivered her the money, made ſuch un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feigned proteſtations of his innocence, that moved the Judge to pity, and to be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve that he was indeed wronged; wherefore he ſaid to the poor man, <hi>Go run after her quickly, and if thou canſt get thy money from her, thou ſhalt have it;</hi> thus overtaking her, he ſets upon her, but proves ſo weak in the matter, that ſhe
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:51789:21"/>
beat him heavily within ſight of all the people. Then the Judge commanded her to be brought back, and ſaid, <hi>Could this man raviſh thee, and thou are ſo able to reſiſt him? Give him his money, and pay him all his charges; and for your wicked<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs I ſhall command that you be well whipped.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="96" type="jest">
               <head>96.</head>
               <p>When Guineys were firſt coined, they were very rare in the Countrey, and hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>py was he that could ſee one; one there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore that came from <hi>London,</hi> more gal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lant than wiſe, ſeeing the Countrey peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple ſo eager to ſee them, <hi>Alas,</hi> ſaid he, throwing down one or two, <hi>theſe are ſo common at</hi> London, <hi>that you cannot receive forty ſhillings, but you ſhall have five or ſix whether you will or no.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="97" type="jest">
               <head>97.</head>
               <p>One lighting a Candle, and ſtriving to ſtick it in a Candleſtick, it often fell out of the Socket, at which he ſaid in choller, <hi>That he thought the Devil did poſſeſs the Candle. Why do you wonder,</hi> ſaid his Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>panion, <hi>if it cannot ſtand? Do you not ſee that 'tis light-headed?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="98" type="jest">
               <pb n="40" facs="tcp:51789:22"/>
               <head>98.</head>
               <p>An ingenious perſon being asked the interpretation of an obſcure Riddle, ſaid nothing, which made the propounder ſo much the more deſirous to hear his an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer. <hi>Pardon me, for why ſhould I,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>loſe that, which as it is, yields me ſo much trouble?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="99" type="jest">
               <head>99.</head>
               <p>A poor man willing to imbrace any ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſt imployment, offered his ſervice to a Gentleman at ſuch a price; <hi>Why, I can buy a Fool,</hi> ſaid be, <hi>mocking the poor mans condition, for that rate: Do then,</hi> replied he, <hi>and you will have two.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="100" type="jest">
               <head>100.</head>
               <p>Two men ſcolding, the wiſer went a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>way, but the other followed after; brawl<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, and condemning him for running a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>way? <hi>Alas,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>though you have pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er to give bad words, I have not to hear them.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="101" type="jest">
               <head>101.</head>
               <p>A fine mouthed Scholar, ſeeing a Spar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>row mute on his companions hat, ſaid, to put the matter in fine language, <hi>Sir, A Sparrow has untruſſed a point upon your hat.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="102" type="jest">
               <pb n="41" facs="tcp:51789:22"/>
               <head>102.</head>
               <p>A School-maſter being very angry one day with one of his young Scholars for writing his name upon the wainſcote, went about to whip him; but the Boy begging earneſtly, the Maſter ſaid, <hi>He's a Fool and ever ſhall, that writes his name upon the Wall: Sirrah, What ſay you to that?</hi> To which the Lad made anſwer, <hi>He's a Fool and ever ſhall, that takes a Wainſcote for a Wall.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="103" type="jest">
               <head>103.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>One being much intreated to warm his fingers,</hi> I thank you Sir, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> I do not uſe to ſtand upon my hands.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="104" type="jest">
               <head>104.</head>
               <p>A young Gentleman, to ſave the laſh, threw himſelf at his Maſters feet; but be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing afterwards blamed by his Friends for ſo debaſing himſelf, <hi>'Tis not my fault,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>but his, if his ears be in his feet.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="105" type="jest">
               <head>105.</head>
               <p>A young Scholar drinking Mum with a Gentleman, the Gentleman thinking to poſe him, ſaid, <hi>Pray how do you decline</hi> 
                  <gap reason="foreign">
                     <desc>〈 in non-Latin alphabet 〉</desc>
                  </gap>? but he wittily ſaid, <gap reason="foreign">
                     <desc>〈 in non-Latin alphabet 〉</desc>
                  </gap>.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="106" type="jest">
               <pb n="42" facs="tcp:51789:23"/>
               <head>106.</head>
               <p>A witty Scholar once asked money o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> his Patron, <hi>Why, have you not often told <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </hi> ſays his Patron, <hi>that Scholars never wa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ed money? 'Tis true,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>but I a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> now a little in haſte, I will talk with you that by and by.</hi> So his Patron gave hi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> money, which having received, <hi>No<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </hi> ſays he, <hi>do Scholars want money?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="107" type="jest">
               <head>107.</head>
               <p>One being chid by his Friends <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> wearing his nails ſo long, <hi>I can aſſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> you,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>I pare them every foot.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="108" type="jest">
               <head>108.</head>
               <p>After the ſad and diſmal Fire in <hi>Lond<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </hi> when nothing was left ſtanding but ruin<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> one paſſing by as they were pulling dow<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> a wall; <hi>Have a care, have a care,</hi> cr<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> he to the Labourers, <hi>or you will pull dow<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> the foundation upon your head.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="109" type="jest">
               <head>109.</head>
               <p>An arch youth ſupping among his fe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>low Scholars at a Boarding-School whe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> they were, ſeeing them carve too buſi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> and cut him clearly out of Common moreover when they had done, to jeer hi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> and throw the bones at him, went privi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> behind one of them, and lifting up his le<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> like the creature that feeds upon bone<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> piſſed upon him.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="110" type="jest">
               <pb n="43" facs="tcp:51789:23"/>
               <head>110.</head>
               <p>A Scholar of <hi>Cambridge</hi> in the time of the Aſſizes, ſeeing a Boy in the Caſtle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward throwing ſtones at the Gallows, <hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ave a care, Sirrah,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>you do not <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> the mark.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="111" type="jest">
               <head>111.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Some Companions talking concerning Minerals and Metals, one ſtarted the Queſtion at laſt,</hi> Why the two nobleſt Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tals, Gold and Silver, one lookt but pale, the other ſo white? Becauſe, <hi>anſwered an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>other,</hi> they have both ſo many that ly in wait for them.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="112" type="jest">
               <head>112.</head>
               <p>Look, look, <hi>ſaid a Scholar to his Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>panion,</hi> how the Townſmen laugh at you? And other Fools, perhaps, <hi>replied the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther,</hi> laugh at them; but neither do they mind fools, nor I them.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="113" type="jest">
               <head>113.</head>
               <p>A Tobaconiſt, whoſe wits were now grown dry with ſmoaking, and his brains probably conſumed to aſhes, when ſome commended this mans Tobacco, others that, <hi>Say what you pleaſe, Gentlemen,</hi> quoth he, <hi>but a clearer Tobacco you never ſaw, for I am ſure it hath neither leaves nor ſtalks.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="114" type="jest">
               <pb n="44" facs="tcp:51789:24"/>
               <head>114.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>The ſame perſon probably, hear<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> much ſwearing in a Bowling green, ſai<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </hi> Fie Gentlemen, 'Tis Gods great men the Bowling Green doth not fall upon yo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> heads.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="115" type="jest">
               <head>115.</head>
               <p>'Tis farther reported by ſome, th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> the ſame man ſitting at Supper, his C<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> paſſed too and fro through his Arms offending his mouth with her tail; whe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> upon in a rage <hi>Don Quixot</hi> like, he c<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> off the tip of her tail moſt valiantly: <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <hi>think now, Miſtriſs Puſs, I have given y<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> an Ear mark.</hi> The Cat taking it ill, fo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> the preſent abſents her ſelf all that night but the next morning, knowing her M<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſter was a man that never let the Sun ſe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> upon his anger; ſhe came after her wont<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ed manner, to expreſs her kindneſs to him by ſtanding in his way. <hi>Why how now you troubleſome Bitch,</hi> ſays he, <hi>are you come again? I thought I had given you your break<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>faſt laſt night?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="116" type="jest">
               <head>116.</head>
               <p>A young Boy throwing ſtones one day amongſt a crowd of people, <hi>Have a care,</hi> ſays a Gentleman, paſſing by, <hi>perhaps you may hit your Father.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="117" type="jest">
               <pb n="45" facs="tcp:51789:24"/>
               <head>117.</head>
               <p>A Carpenter being at work in a Bowl<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Green, was asked, what he was a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout? <hi>I am a making,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>a Bench for <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> ſtanders by, to ſit upon.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="118" type="jest">
               <head>118.</head>
               <p>The firſt night King <hi>Charles</hi> the Firſt came into <hi>Ragland Caſtle,</hi> his Majeſty de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſired to ſee the great Tower, where his Lordſhip uſed to keep his Treaſure, and ſpake to Doctor <hi>Baily</hi> to fetch the Keys. He ran down to the Marquiſs, and ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quainted him with the Kings pleaſure, who would needs bring the Keys himſelf to the King. When the King ſaw the Marquiſs bringing the Keys himſelf, he ſaid, <hi>My Lord, There are ſome men ſo unreaſonable, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> to make me believe, that your Lordſhip hath good ſtore of Gold yet left within this Tower; but knowing how I have exhauſted you, could never have believed it, until now I ſee you will not truſt the Keys with any but your ſelf.</hi> To which the Marquiſs an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwered, <hi>Sir, I was ſo far from giving your Majeſty any ſuch occaſion of thought by this tender of my duty; that I proteſt unto you, I was once reſolved your Majeſty ſhould have lain there, but that I was loath to commit you to the Tower.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="119" type="jest">
               <pb n="46" facs="tcp:51789:25"/>
               <head>119.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>A Scholar meeting a poor ignorant Pea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſant on the Road,</hi> How far friend, <hi>ſay<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> he,</hi> to Cambridge? By my faith Sir, <hi>ſay<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> he,</hi> I do not know, but from <hi>Cambridge</hi> t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> this Town is counted ſeven miles.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="120" type="jest">
               <head>120.</head>
               <p>One having ſent for a Phyſitian to his Daughter, that was deſperately ill; the Doctor being come, and having examined the Caſe how ſhe was ſeeing her lie on her back, adviſed her to lie rather on her ſide: <hi>Ay Sir,</hi> ſaid her Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, <hi>I have alwayes told her, her bac<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> was the beſt ſide to lie upon; and ſhe would never believe me.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="121" type="jest">
               <head>121.</head>
               <p>A certain perſon being asked by hi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> friend, why he wore his Stockings with the wrong ſides outwards; <hi>Oh,</hi> ſaid he <hi>being forced to wear the one ſo, I turn the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther alſo; that it may not be ſo eaſily percei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved. But pray, why,</hi> quoth the other, <hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> you wear one with the wrong ſide outwards<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Why, becauſe,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>it hath a hole <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> the other ſide.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="122" type="jest">
               <pb n="47" facs="tcp:51789:25"/>
               <head>122.</head>
               <p>A Crew of boon Companions, in the height of their mirth, began to be capti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons and quarrel; ſo <hi>Thomas</hi> threw a piece of a Tobacco-pipe in <hi>John's</hi> face; but <hi>Tho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mas</hi> denied it and cleared himſelf. <hi>Well 'twas ill done of you</hi> Thomas <hi>though,</hi> quoth <hi>John, whoever did it.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="123" type="jest">
               <head>123.</head>
               <p>Two Scholars had made a match one night to go ſteal Rabbets in a Warren, the one that was ſet to watch, when the Rabbets came, cried out, <hi>Ecce cuniculi multi;</hi> at which the Coneys ran again in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to their Burrows. The others ſeeing the ſhort ſpoiled, chid him for ſo doing. <hi>Why who knew,</hi> ſays he, <hi>that they underſtood Latine?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="124" type="jest">
               <head>124.</head>
               <p>One quarrelling in his Cups with his Companion at the Tavern, was ſo furi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous and violent, that he would have bea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten him immediately: and being hindred from ſtriking by the reſt of the Compa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny, <hi>You ſhall not think to eſcape ſo,</hi> ſaid he, in a rage, <hi>I proteſt I will kick you down ſtairs whereſoever I meet you.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="125" type="jest">
               <pb n="48" facs="tcp:51789:26"/>
               <head>125.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman taking compaſſion of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> poor fool that went up and down th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Streets almoſt naked in the extremity o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Winter, gave him an old Coat; not lon<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> after one called him and gave him a ha<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> penny loaf: <hi>Oh pray,</hi> quoth he, to th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Donor, <hi>let me leave my coat till I have carried home my half penny loaf, and I wil<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> fetch my coat another time.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="126" type="jest">
               <head>126.</head>
               <p>One ſent for a Phyſician to come to his Coſin, whoſe eyes were very bad and after the Doctor had ſeen the Patient who was indeed in a very deſperate con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dition: <hi>Pray Sir,</hi> ſays the Gentleman, <hi>how doth my Coſin?</hi> The Doctor, who was always of a very debonaire humor and that by his facetious ſayings could comfort the weakeſt Patient, replied, <hi>Sir, you need not doubt of your Coſin's health; he's well enough if he can ſee it.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="127" type="jest">
               <head>127.</head>
               <p>A very fat Gentleman riding through a Countrey Town, his Belly ſticking out before him, the people cry'd aloud to him, <hi>That he had miſtaken, in placing his Port-mantle before him.</hi> To which he replied, <hi>Where ſhould I place it better
<pb n="49" facs="tcp:51789:26"/>
when I come amongſt ſo many Rogues and Thiefs?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="128" type="jest">
               <head>128.</head>
               <p>One going a ſhooting in the hard wea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, would have borrowed ſome money of his friend; <hi>You have no need of money,</hi> ſaid the other merrily, <hi>for if in any place you have any thing to pay, you may leave your Gun to diſcharge the ſhot.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="129" type="jest">
               <head>129.</head>
               <p>When King <hi>Henry</hi> the Eighth paſſed by <hi>Kings-Colledge</hi> Chappel in <hi>Cambridge,</hi> that famous Fabrick built by King <hi>Henry</hi> the VI, his Jeſter ſaid to him, <hi>Harry, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> and I built this fine Chappel.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="130" type="jest">
               <head>130.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman eating a very hot Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtard, let a great fart, but to ſave the ſhame, being before much honourable Company; <hi>'Tis well,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>you are but, otherwiſe I would have batcht you out.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="131" type="jest">
               <head>131.</head>
               <p>Three men gave their Hoſteſs Forty pounds to keep for them, with this charge, not to deliver the money to any one ſin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gle, unleſs they came all three together: Not long after one came for the money, and by words and many great ſigns that he
<pb n="50" facs="tcp:51789:27"/>
came from the reſt, got the money, and then went away beyond Sea. The others hearing of this, came and demanded the reaſon, why ſhe parted with the money contrary to the charge given her; and thereupon ſued her at Law for the Forty pound; at laſt by the force of one Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cellor the poor woman was almoſt caſt and forced to pay the ſaid ſum: when a Lawyer who had diligently obſerved the Cauſe, ſtarted up and ſaid to the Judge, <hi>The charge given to this woman, my Lord, concerning the money, was to deliver it to theſe three all together, and no otherwiſe; let theſe two bring the other with them, and their money is ready to be paid down.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="132" type="jest">
               <head>132.</head>
               <p>A wiſe Judge, when a party had forged a Will, and many ſwore to it, that they were the laſt words that came out of the deceaſed perſons mouth; in ſo much that the true heir was almoſt caſt; <hi>But were they not put into his mouth,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>which words ſilenced all, and recovered the Eſtate.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="133" type="jest">
               <head>133.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>A certain Cuſtomer asking his Barber,</hi> Where he might have ſome water to waſh his hands? Yonder, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> at the other
<pb n="51" facs="tcp:51789:27"/>
end of the room you will find ſome, in that empty Tub.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="134" type="jest">
               <head>134.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>One ſpeaking of the wind, ſaid,</hi> It was the moſt changeable thing in the world; for I went, <hi>ſays he,</hi> up Cheapſide in the morning, and it was in my back; and in leſs than half an hour afterwards, when I re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turned, I found it in my face.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="135" type="jest">
               <head>135.</head>
               <p>A Carpenter paſſing by with a Deal Board on his Shoulder, hit a Gentleman on the Head with the end of it; where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon he perceiving his fault, cry'd, <hi>Have a care Sir; Why,</hi> quoth he, <hi>do you intend to hit me again.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="136" type="jest">
               <head>136.</head>
               <p>Some Gentlemen having been at Bowls, went at laſt to a Shooting Match, but be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing unexperienced in that Art, erred much from the Mark on either ſide; whereupon one that ſtood by, went and ſate him juſt at the bottom of the But: and being asked the reaſon, <hi>Becauſe,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>I am afraid if I ſtand any where elſe they ſhould hit me.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="137" type="jest">
               <head>137.</head>
               <p>One complained much of the Glaſier, ſaying, he was very unreaſonable to ask
<pb n="52" facs="tcp:51789:28"/>
ſo much for Soder as two pence a foot; <hi>Truly,</hi> ſaid another, <hi>I think it is alwayes So dear.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="138" type="jest">
               <head>138.</head>
               <p>A proper young and handſome Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tleman fell in love with an old, rich, and miſerable Councellors onely Daughter, but deſpairing ever to get her Fathers con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent, becauſe of the inequality of his E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtate compared with hers; he made it his buſineſs firſt to make ſure of her good will, and then he uſed this witty Strata<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gem: He goes one day to her Father, and clapping five Guineys into his hand, deſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red his beſt advice in the caſe he ſhould acquaint him with, which was, That he loved a fair and young Lady, had her conſent, and nothing was wanting but the good will of her friends; which ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vertheleſs he feared he could never ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain, for ſuch certain reaſons, without ſome ſubtil Stratagem: The old man, on whom the Gold began to work, in hopes of another ſuch Fee, puts him off till the next day, that he might the better conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der of the matter. The young Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man therefore failed not to return at the time appointed, with the other five Gui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neys to haſten the matter, whereupon the
<pb n="53" facs="tcp:51789:28"/>
old Councellor told him there was but one way, that was, He ſhould get the Lady privately to be married to him; and to that end he would give him a Note to a certain Prieſt of his acquaintance, that ſhould joyn them in Matrimony with all ſpeed and ſecrecy. Thus the young man by his ſubtilty out-witted the old Councel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lor, got a Note under his own hand to marry his Daughter, and then brought his Wife to ask her Fathers bleſſing: which Stratagem ſo pleaſed the old man, that not reſpecting his Sons low con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dition, he gave his Daughter a large Dowry.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="139" type="jest">
               <head>139.</head>
               <p>A Clown newly come up to <hi>London,</hi> that was a rich Farmer's Son, yet but poor in Cloaths at the preſent, was huge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly taken at the ſight of a Sedan, and bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gained with the Bearers to carry him to ſuch a place. The Sedan-men ſeeing this Clown's curioſity, unhaſp'd the bot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tom of the Sedan privately and took him <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>n; where b<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ing ſeated, wh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>n they beg<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>n to hoiſt the Sedan, the Countreyman ſtood on the ground with his legs: thus did they hurry him through all the dirty kennels in their way, till they brought
<pb n="54" facs="tcp:51789:29"/>
him to his Lodging This man not know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing but others uſed to be carried, or ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther driven after the ſame manner, gave them their due hire, and when he return<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed into the Countrey again, began a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongſt the reſt of his news, and all the fine things he had ſeen at <hi>London,</hi> to tell That he had been carried in a Sedan wherefore every one was deſirous to know how it was? <hi>Why it is,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>like <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> Watch houſe, onely 'tis covered with lea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther; and were it not for the name of a Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dan, one had as good go on foot.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="140" type="jest">
               <head>140.</head>
               <p>One meeting his Friend in the Street, where was a great ſtop of Coaches, that none could paſs; asked him where he was going? <hi>To the Market,</hi> replied the other <hi>to buy ſome meat. Well then go by,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> you can, farewell.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="141" type="jest">
               <head>141.</head>
               <p>A Countreyman coming to <hi>Londo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </hi> into a Bookſellers Shop, to buy a Bible, the man ſhewed him one that had a Patch in the Cover; the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>treyman diſpleaſed at that, would ſee more; whereat the Maſter came out, asking his man what his Chapman would have? <hi>Sir,</hi> ſaid his boy, <hi>he wants a Bi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble,
<pb n="55" facs="tcp:51789:29"/>
and he doth not like this.</hi> Then his Maſter looking on it, <hi>Why Sirrah,</hi> ſaid he, to his Apprentice, <hi>have I but one dou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble covered Bible in all the Shop, and you muſt ſhew every one this. O pray,</hi> ſaid the Countreyman, <hi>let me have it by all means, if it be double covered; for I would fain have a laſting one.</hi> And ſo paid down the price moſt willingly.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="142" type="jest">
               <head>142.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Thomas Frog</hi> and Mr. <hi>John Rain,</hi> meet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing accidentally at a broad kennel in the Street, and knowing one another, <hi>Frog</hi> was ſtill hindring <hi>Rain,</hi> and would fain be leaping over; but <hi>Rain</hi> ſtriving to get o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver, <hi>Frog</hi> began to ſcold at him for dirt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing his Stockings. <hi>I think theſe Frogs are alwayes croaking in wet weather,</hi> ſays <hi>Rain. So you muſt expect,</hi> ſaid <hi>Frog</hi> again, <hi>till the</hi> Rain <hi>be over.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="143" type="jest">
               <head>143.</head>
               <p>An Univerſity Scholar being hot in diſcourſe at the Table in the Hall, and ſo loud that the Fellows heard him, the Dean ſent to him to be quiet, after this manner by the Servitor, <hi>Vir ſapit qui pauca loquitur:</hi> To which he returned this anſwer, <hi>Vir loquitur qui pauca ſapit.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="144" type="jest">
               <pb n="56" facs="tcp:51789:30"/>
               <head>144.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman being choaked with a Honey-comb, his friends began to be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moan him. <hi>Why make you ſuch lamentati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on,</hi> ſaid another, <hi>never man died a ſweeter death.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="145" type="jest">
               <head>145.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>One ſeeing a Ladies Legs, as ſhe lifted up her Coats a little too high, he ſaid to her,</hi> Madam, you have a very handſome pair of Twins. You are miſtaken Sir, <hi>ſaid ſhe,</hi> for I have had one between them.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="146" type="jest">
               <head>146.</head>
               <p>A Miniſter marrying a couple of his friends, told them afterwards in merri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, that if after they diſliked, they ſhould come to him again, and he would un-marry them. So this Countrey Cou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple go home, and are very merry for the firſt week or two; but at laſt, diſſention ariſing between them, they both came again to the Prieſt to be divorced. Here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon he fetcheth out a great Hatchet, and asks who had the greateſt deſire to leave the other firſt? <hi>For,</hi> ſays he, <hi>I have mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ried you till death you do depart; and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore it is expedient that I kill one of you.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="147" type="jest">
               <pb n="57" facs="tcp:51789:30"/>
               <head>147.</head>
               <p>A Barber being a Tobaconiſt, and ſel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling both Hair and Tobacco, accidentally in the ſame ounce to his Cuſtomer; for as much as ſome looſe Hair ſcattered by chance into the Tobacco; the next time his Cuſtomer met him and complained of his ſelling ſuch bad Tobacco, that was full of Hair. <hi>Truly,</hi> replied he, <hi>I get much by ſelling ſuch pennyworths; an ounce of Hair that coſts me ten ſhillings, for three pence.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="148" type="jest">
               <head>148.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>A tall Miniſter told a ſhort one ſcoffing<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly,</hi> That he looked in a Pulpit like a Collar of Brawn in a Diſh. And you, <hi>replied he,</hi> look like a Peſtle in a Mortar.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="149" type="jest">
               <head>149.</head>
               <p>At a great Feaſt, where many Gueſts were preſent, there was ſerved up a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongſt other good Diſhes, a great Tur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ky Pie, i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> whoſe ſides the Cats had eat a great hole this gave the Maſter occaſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on to be angry with his Servants for their negligence: but one of his Gueſts ſaid, <hi>Pray blame not your Servants Sir, 'tis enough it hath eſcaped the Turky-Pie-Cats ſo well.</hi>
               </p>
               <pb n="56" facs="tcp:51789:31"/>
               <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="57" facs="tcp:51789:31"/>
               <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
               </gap>
            </div>
            <div n="150" type="jest">
               <pb n="58" facs="tcp:51789:32"/>
               <head>150.</head>
               <p>'Twas at the ſame Feaſt probably, that a Rice Fool was brought up to the Table, when many of the Gueſts doubted what it was. One wittily ſaid, <hi>Per riſum multum poſſis cognoſcere ſtultum.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="151" type="jest">
               <head>151.</head>
               <p>Some Gentlemen quarrelling at Table, one to reprehend the other of his great uſe of Tobacco and the foulneſs of his Mouth, called him a foul Tobacco-Pipe. The other readily told him he was a dent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Quart-pot. The ſtrangeneſs of this Metaphor ſtuck in his mind, and made him very urgent to know the reaſon; <hi>Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>you ſeem to have more in you than you have.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="152" type="jest">
               <head>152.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman of the <hi>Temple</hi> being new<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly come up to <hi>London,</hi> told his Friend, he had brought up a Horſe with him, and would ſell it. <hi>What have you him at your Chamber?</hi> ſaid the other.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="153" type="jest">
               <head>153.</head>
               <p>A meer Scholar ſent one day for <hi>Tim</hi> the S<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>th to hang up two Pictures, and asking him, when he had done, what he muſt have? <hi>Sir,</hi> ſaith <hi>Tim, there are two Ten-penny Nails, and what you pleaſe
<pb n="59" facs="tcp:51789:32"/>
for my labour. Well there Sirrah are two Shillings,</hi> ſaid, the Gentleman, <hi>that is, a Groat for thy pains, and twenty pence for thy Nails; Go thy ways.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="154" type="jest">
               <head>154.</head>
               <p>A Humoriſt calling for a reckoning, found there was ten pence to pay; where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore breaking the Glaſs he had in his hand againſt the wall, <hi>Dam you, there's a ſhilling Sirrah for you;</hi> ſaid he to the Tapſter.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="155" type="jest">
               <head>155.</head>
               <p>A man being abuſed by many ſcanda<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lous reproaches of his neighbour, as cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling him Rogue, his Wife Whore, and the like, ſued him at Law; but finding af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter much trouble thoſe words would bear no Action, he was ſo incenſed, that as he ſtood in the middle of the Court, he cry'd aloud, <hi>My Lord, you are a Rogue, your Wife <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>s a Whore, and your Children are all Baſtards.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="156" type="jest">
               <head>156.</head>
               <p>Two Boys going together to School, met with one whoſe name was <hi>Pontius <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>rben,</hi> a Rag of the Law, that was not well in his wits; <hi>Lets us call yonder fellow Pontius Pilate,</hi> ſays one of them, and then ran away: Whereupon the man be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>came
<pb n="60" facs="tcp:51789:33"/>
ſo furious, that the other was for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ced alſo to double his pace, and ſave him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>felf in the School houſe: Preſently in came the man, and would have beaten him, but that the Maſter took him off, and promiſed to whip him ſoundly: So at every l<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ſh he asked him if ever he would ſay ag<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>in <hi>Pontius Pilate?</hi> To which he anſwered, crying, <hi>No Sir.</hi> The next d<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>y at Prayers, when the Boy came to theſe words in the Creed, <hi>Who ſuffered und<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>r</hi> Pontius Pilate, he remembred his fault, and ſaid, <hi>Who ſuffered under</hi> Pon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tius Urben.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="157" type="jest">
               <head>157.</head>
               <p>Other young Scholars went up into a Stee<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>le to get a Sparrow-Hawk's Neſt, that was in a hole of the Wall; and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe it was juſt over a Window, but juſt out of their reach, they agreed that the ſtrongeſt of the two ſhould hold out a Board for the other to ſtand upon and take the Neſt; this done, he that took the Neſt, call'd out to the other, That 'twas a brave Neſt, and there were five in it, but that he would have three: <hi>Nay, but I will have three,</hi> ſays he that held the Board, <hi>or I will let you fall:</hi> and thereup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the other not conſenting to it, he let
<pb n="61" facs="tcp:51789:33"/>
him fall. The youth, though he fell ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry high, when he came to the ground, and received no damage, he ran away crying, <hi>Now you Rogue you ſhall have none of them.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="158" type="jest">
               <head>158.</head>
               <p>If I were unmarried, <hi>ſaid one,</hi> then would I wed again. Marry then, <hi>quoth the other,</hi> you would ſtill be in the ſame lock.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="159" type="jest">
               <head>159.</head>
               <p>One returning from the Market, where he had bought a new pair of Shoes, met in his way with a poor young woman that begged on him. <hi>Truly,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>I have no money to give thee, but if thou wilt let me lie with thee, thou ſhalt have theſe Shoes.</hi> The reward, and a little good na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture, made her willing to put on the Shoes; but when he had done the work, he would have his Shoes again, and not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding her reſiſtance took them by force; ſaying, <hi>Let him that rides thee next ſhoe thee for me.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="160" type="jest">
               <head>160.</head>
               <p>A Countreyman was uſed when he clove wood, to cry <hi>Hem</hi> at every ſtroke, and his Wife obſerving it, that then he ſtruck with moſt force, bid him at night,
<pb n="62" facs="tcp:51789:34"/>
when they were together, cry <hi>Hem<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> No,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>I muſt not do ſo now; for I intend onely to bore, not to cleave thee.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="161" type="jest">
               <head>161.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Ben J<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>hnſon,</hi> the great Poet, when the Biſhop ſent him from his Table an excel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lent Diſh of Fiſh, but without Drink, ſaid,
<q>
                     <lg>
                        <l>
                           <hi>Mittitur in diſco mihi piſcis ab Archiepiſce</hi>
                        </l>
                        <l>
                           <hi>po ne ponatur, quia potus non mihi datur.</hi>
                        </l>
                     </lg>
                     <lg>
                        <l>In a Diſh came Fiſh</l>
                        <l>From the Arch Biſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>Hop</l>
                        <l>was not there,</l>
                        <l>Becauſe there was no Beer.</l>
                     </lg>
                  </q>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="162" type="jest">
               <head>162.</head>
               <p>One having a Horſe that was very har<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy, and had but little ſtomack, though with himſelf he might eaſily by degree bring him to live without Hay or Oats and ſo ſubſtracted daily ſomething fro<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> his Meat, till at laſt the Horſe died; an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> when afterwards he was carrying him o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> in a Cart to lay him in the Fields for th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Crows, and his neighbours asked him how his Horſe came to die? <hi>Why, thought,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>to have made him live <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <pb n="63" facs="tcp:51789:34"/>
nothing; and juſt as I brought him to it, he died.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="163" type="jest">
               <head>163.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Mr</hi> Fuller <hi>and Mr.</hi> Sparrowhawk, <hi>walk<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing together, amongſt other merry diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>courſe, ſaid</hi> Fuller, What difference is there between an Owl and a Sparrowhawk? Why, <hi>ſaid</hi> Sparrowhawk, 'Tis fuller in the body, fuller in the face, and fuller all over.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="164" type="jest">
               <head>164.</head>
               <p>A wiſe Barber having been to trim a Doctor at night, was offered a Candle to light him down ſtairs; which having taken, and light himſelf down, he brought up again, and returned thanks, and ſo went away in the dark.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="165" type="jest">
               <head>165.</head>
               <p>A Welſhman hearing another Malefa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctor that was try'd juſt before him, ſay, concerning a Mare he had ſtoln, <hi>That he brought it up from a Colt;</hi> when he came to be examined of a Sword he had ſharked, ſaid, <hi>That truly, by St.</hi> David, <hi>'twas his own; for he bred it up of a Dag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="166" type="jest">
               <head>166.</head>
               <p>One commended another before much company, for having very handſome
<pb n="64" facs="tcp:51789:35"/>
Legs. <hi>Yes, but,</hi> ſays the ſimple Rogue, <hi>I have got two pair of Stockings on.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="167" type="jest">
               <head>167.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>One ſeeing his son do untowardly,</hi> Why Sirrah, <hi>ſays he,</hi> did you ever ſee me do ſo, when I was a boy?</p>
            </div>
            <div n="168" type="jest">
               <head>168.</head>
               <p>A blundering Doctor going out one night wi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>h his m<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>n to ſee a fire that was in <hi>Cambridge,</hi> on the backſide of the Town; and co<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>ing amongſt the Crowd: <hi>Go</hi> Thomas, ſaid he, <hi>to his Man, ſee how the fire is.</hi> But his man being hindred by thoſe that laded water out of a Ditch, from going over the Bridge; returned to his Maſter, and told him he could not get near. <hi>What,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>you are afraid <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> be burnt in your bed, now let me come and ſee.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="169" type="jest">
               <head>169.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Mr.</hi> Ralph Amner <hi>of</hi> Windſor, <hi>com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monly called the</hi> Bull-Sp<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>aker; <hi>when he was very ſick, and at the point to die<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                  </hi> Well, <hi>ſaid he to his friends,</hi> when I am dead, write only this on my Tomb for my Epitaph, Here lies honeſt <hi>Ralph,</hi> as dead as any man living.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="170" type="jest">
               <pb n="65" facs="tcp:51789:35"/>
               <head>170.</head>
               <p>One ſaid, Doctor <hi>Wilſon</hi> the Muſick Maſter, when he firſt fell ſick, lookt ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry thin; <hi>Can you wonder at that,</hi> ſaid an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>other, <hi>when Camelion like he lives by the Air?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="171" type="jest">
               <head>171.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>The Gardiners place of a Colledge be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing void, a certain perſon put in for it; the Dean asked him if he underſtood Gardening?</hi> No truly, <hi>replied he,</hi> but I will hire one to do the work. Nay then, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> you cannot expect to have the place; <hi>and ſo ſent him away. But as he was go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing througb the Court, he calls after him,</hi> Now it comes in my mind, <hi>ſays he,</hi> there is a place void, which I think would do ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry well for you; and that is the Greek Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſſor's. Alas Sir, <hi>ſaid the man,</hi> I un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derſtand not that language. Oh but, <hi>repli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed the Dean,</hi> you may hire one to do the work for you.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="172" type="jest">
               <head>172.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>When Mr.</hi> Button <hi>died,</hi> Od ſlife, <hi>ſaid one,</hi> are graves become Button h<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>les?</p>
            </div>
            <div n="173" type="jest">
               <head>173.</head>
               <p>One praying in <hi>Paul</hi>'s Cathedral, his Hat was ſtoln from him; of which when he complained to the ſtanders by, <hi>You
<pb n="66" facs="tcp:51789:36"/>
ſhould,</hi> ſaid one, <hi>have watch'd as well as pray'd.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="174" type="jest">
               <head>174.</head>
               <p>An impotent Gentleman having marri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed a rich young Gentlewoman, whom he could not ſatisfie, gave a young luſty Gal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lant Fifty pounds a year to do the work: But his Waiting-man ſeeing this Gallant one day with his Miſtriſs, ran to ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quaint his Maſter; but he, fained as if he were in a ſleep, and gave no anſwer: which made him cry the more urgently, That his Marriage-Bed was defiled. When his Maſter ſaw he would not be quiet, <hi>Peace, peace,</hi> ſays he, <hi>I give him Fifty pound a year for doing it<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Ah, Sir,</hi> repli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed the man, <hi>had I known that, I would have done it for half the money.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="175" type="jest">
               <head>175.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>When a Tallow-Chandler in the Neighbourhood died, one ſaid,</hi> 'Twas ſtrange that he who made ſo many weeks, could make his days no longer.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="176" type="jest">
               <head>176.</head>
               <p>A notable Strumpet having given her Footman a new Livery, 'twas his fortune as he went on ſome Errand, to meet a Gentleman that knew his Lady; this Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tleman calls after him, deſiring to know
<pb n="67" facs="tcp:51789:36"/>
of him whom he ſerved; the Footman told him ſuch a Lady. <hi>A Lady,</hi> quoth the other, <hi>ſhe's a damn'd Whore.</hi> So the Footman in vindication of his Miſtriſſes honour, drew; but the Gentleman, more expert at his weapon, ſoon diſarms him, and kicks him into the kennel, and ſpoils all his bravery. The Footman coming home in that pickle, tells his Lady how it came; ſaying, He hoped, that ſince in vindication of her Ladiſhips honour, he had hazarded his life, ſhe would be plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed to give him a new Livery. <hi>Begone you Rogue,</hi> ſays ſhe, <hi>I ſhall have enough to do, to give you a new Livery for every one that calls me whore.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="177" type="jest">
               <head>177.</head>
               <p>A Welchman ſhitting from a Bridge, <hi>Good ſhit, by</hi> Davy, ſaid he, <hi>what a De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vil no plump;</hi> for he expected to hear his excrement fall in the water, but all the while ſhit in his Coat-pocket.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="178" type="jest">
               <head>178.</head>
               <p>I ſee you do all under colour, <hi>ſaid the Glazier to the Painter, ſeeing him daub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing ſome Rails.</hi> Go your wayes for a Rogue, <hi>replied he,</hi> you'l never leave picking quar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rels.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="179" type="jest">
               <head>179.</head>
               <pb n="68" facs="tcp:51789:37"/>
               <p>Three great Maſters of their Trade, a Vaulter, a Barber, and a Fencer, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended together, who was the beſt expe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rienced in his Art. The Vaulter leap<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> and ſate a Stag in his full courſe, the Barber ſhaved a Goat running, the Fen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cer in a rainy day, ſo brandiſhed his Sword over his head, that no drop of rain fell upon him. Let him judge which was the beſt that believes the Story.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="180" type="jest">
               <head>180.</head>
               <p>A Fool that ow'd a Carpenter a ſhrewd good turn, finding him one day in a ſleep upon a Form, took the Axe and cut off his head; then cama into the Houſe laughing: whereof when he was asked the reaſon, <hi>It is,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>to think how the Carpenter will look for his head whe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> he wakes.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="181" type="jest">
               <head>181.</head>
               <p>Two Fools lying together, a great diſpute aroſe; Who ſhould lie in the middle of thoſe two, and could not be ended; till one more wiſe, laid a Broom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtaff between them.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="182" type="jest">
               <pb n="69" facs="tcp:51789:37"/>
               <head>182.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>A Maid accuſed a youth for raviſhing her before the Juſtice,</hi> This is a great <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>rime; <hi>ſaid he,</hi> indeed; and did he never <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>e with you before? If he did — then. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ſes, if it pleaſe you Sir, <hi>ſaid ſhe,</hi> at leaſt ſix or ſeven times.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="183" type="jest">
               <head>183.</head>
               <p>Some merry Companions talking of what rare pieces of Clockwork they had ſeen, one ſaid he had ſeen ſomething far ſtranger, which was a Merchanick that pull'd out of his Pocket three little Cocks, one he call'd a French, the other a Dutch, the third an Engliſh one; then taking the French one, he ſtruck him over the head, this made the French Cock cry out, <hi>Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ley veu Francois Monſieur.</hi> The Dutch Cock being ſtruck in like manner, cry'd, <hi>Give me a little Engliſh Beer.</hi> Here he ended his Story, whereupon the Compa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny, and one eſpecially, was very deſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rous to know what the Engliſh Cock ſaid? <hi>Why,</hi> replied he, <hi>it cry'd, Put your Noſe here,</hi> pointing to his Breech, <hi>Put your Noſe here.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="184" type="jest">
               <head>184.</head>
               <p>A Phyſician being to examine a Lad, asked him, Why ſick Perſons were ſaid to
<pb n="70" facs="tcp:51789:38"/>
be Patients? <hi>Becauſe,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>they ſuffer ſo much by the Phyſitian.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="185" type="jest">
               <head>185.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>One ſaid to his Friend,</hi> Sir you are as wiſe as Solomon. <hi>The other replied,</hi> And you are as wiſe as Socrates. Why Socrates? Becauſe, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> Sciebat tantum ſe nihil ſcire.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="186" type="jest">
               <head>186.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>One told his Lady of Pleaſure ſhe was very fruitful.</hi> How can that be, Sir, <hi>ſaid ſhe,</hi> ſince I never had any children? That's nothing, Madam, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> nevertheleſs you bear many.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="187" type="jest">
               <head>187.</head>
               <p>Two Gentlemen, a tall and a ſhort one, woed the ſame Lady; and her Friends li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king both, reſolved to put it to her choice which ſhe would have: Then viewing both well, and comparing their propor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions with her deſires; ſeeing one ſhort, the other tall and luſty; <hi>I will,</hi> ſaid ſhe, <hi>have the long one, if all things are propor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tionable.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="188" type="jest">
               <head>188.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>One ſaid, A Covetous Man was never ſatisfied.</hi> Why ſo? <hi>ſaid his Friend.</hi> Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> 
                  <hi>replied he,</hi> he thinks nothing enough. Why then, <hi>ſaid the other,</hi> he is ſatisfied
<pb n="71" facs="tcp:51789:38"/>
with leaſt, if nothing be enough for him.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="189" type="jest">
               <head>189.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>One told his Wife there was a Law coming out,</hi> That all Cuckolds ſhould be drowned. O pray Husband, <hi>ſaid ſhe,</hi> then learn to ſwim.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="190" type="jest">
               <head>190.</head>
               <p>One called another Baſtard, that was ſo indeed; therefore wittily he anſwered, <hi>Children and Fools tell truth,</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="191" type="jest">
               <head>191.</head>
               <p>A Gentlewoman and her Maid being to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>et up ſome Cloaths againſt Chriſtmaſs day, had ſo delayed the time to the very live, that ſhe her ſelf, her Maid, and a hired Waſherwoman, were all little e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nough to diſpatch them. On the Eve therefore, betimes in the morning, they <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ell to work; and at Breakfaſt, <hi>Here,</hi> ſays the Miſtriſs to her Maid, <hi>fetch a Quart of Ale. Why Miſtriſs if you pleaſe,</hi> ſaid the Waſherwoman, <hi>I will j<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>yn my penny, and we may have three pints. And I will joyn mine too, if you pleaſe,</hi> ſaid the Maid, <hi>and we will have two Quarts. Well then,</hi> ſaid the Miſtriſs, <hi>bring three Quarts; we ſhall work the better: ſo there's my Groat.</hi> Then fell theſe three jolly Waſherwomen
<pb n="72" facs="tcp:51789:39"/>
to toſt it and tipple it ſo long, till it lay raw upon their Stomachs forſooth; and then it came in the Maids head, that a little Brandy would do very well to take away that rawneſs; and therefore offer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed her penny towards it: the hired Wo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man was right, and offered hers. <hi>And here's my two pence,</hi> ſaid the Miſtriſs. <hi>Oh,</hi> ſaid the Maid, <hi>here is a penny too much, what ſhall we do? Why you and I,</hi> ſaid the Waſherman, <hi>will put our pence a pitt<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> more, and we may have half a pint.</hi> This they fell to the Brandy, and at laſt truly the Miſtriſs found her ſelf very ſleepy, and would needs go lie on the Bed to take a little nap to refreſh her ſelf; the Maid ſomething drowſie, followed after: and the poor Woman in the Kitchin, taking the advantage, ſtretcht her ſelf out by the fire. Thus they lay faſt till next morn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, when the Maid awaking, roſe and found the Woman ſleeping in the Kitchin and the fire out; then running to her Neighbours to light ſome Charcoal, to kindle the fire, leaſt her Miſtriſs ſhould be angry; ſhe found there the Roaſt Beef on the Spit, and great preparations for <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>omething extraordinary. So ſhe asked the Maid who dined with them that
<pb n="73" facs="tcp:51789:39"/>
day, that they made ſuch great proviſion? <hi>Why,</hi> ſaid ſhe, <hi>'tis Chriſtmaſs-day.</hi> The Maid aſtoniſhed, ran to acquaint her Miſtriſs, yet could ſcarce perſwade her of the truth, till the Bell toled to Church and took away their doubting.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="192" type="jest">
               <head>192.</head>
               <p>At a Feaſt, where many Citizens and their Wives were met, the chief of their diſcourſe being about Cuckolds; one ask<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed the reaſon why the men wore the horns, when the women onely were in fault? <hi>That is,</hi> ſaid another, <hi>becauſe the man is the head, and where would you have the horns grow elſe.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="193" type="jest">
               <head>193.</head>
               <p>A Countrey Schoolmaſter, read inga Leſſon to his Boys, concerning the Ver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tues in Moral Philoſophy, gave them this general Rule to know Virtues from Vices; <hi>That Virtues conſiſted in the middle, and Vices were extreams:</hi> The next day when he examined, he bid one of his Scholars give an example; and the Boy inſtanced in Virginity. <hi>Why Sirrah,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>who told you Virginity was a Vertue? You did Sir, you ſaid that all Vertues conſiſted in the middle, and ſo doth Virginity.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="194" type="jest">
               <pb n="74" facs="tcp:51789:40"/>
               <head>194.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>A conceited perſon would fain know of his friend what others thought of him?</hi> Why reply'd he, you appear to the wiſe foo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſh, to fools wiſe; what think you of your ſelf?</p>
            </div>
            <div n="195" type="jest">
               <head>195.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman, that had many Chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren, was ſaying one day to his friend, That his Wife was more fertil than his Land. <hi>That may well be,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>for if you are a weary, or won't take pains to make her ſo, others will.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="196" type="jest">
               <head>196.</head>
               <p>When one talking of Sir <hi>Francis Drake</hi>'s good ſucceſs, related how often he came home in ſafety from ſeveral long Voyages. <hi>Truly 'tis ſtrange,</hi> ſaid ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, <hi>in all that time he ne'r was duckt,</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="197" type="jest">
               <head>197.</head>
               <p>One following his Maſter on foot, and ſtroaking his Horſes buttock, the Horſe kick'd him over the ſhins; wherefore he took up a ſtone to throw at him: but in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtead of hitting the Horſe, he hit his Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter over the back. This made his Maſter turn about, and ask what was the matter? <hi>Alas Sir,</hi> ſaid his man, holding his Leg with his hand, <hi>your Horſe hath almoſt
<pb n="75" facs="tcp:51789:40"/>
lamed me. Well then</hi> replied his Maſter, <hi>I muſt put him away; for he kick'd me but juſt now alſo over the back, and 'twas God's mercy, he did not daſh out my brains.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="198" type="jest">
               <head>198.</head>
               <p>One ſaid that ſuch a pocky perſon was very ugly and wondred that any woman would be ſo mad as to accompany him. <hi>Why ſo?</hi> ſaid another, <hi>he is Ven-uſtus enough.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="199" type="jest">
               <head>199.</head>
               <p>A man having been a long journey out of Town, for the more ſpeed of his bu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſineſs, rid poſt home; and after he was at Supper, and in Bed with his Wife, he ſaid to her, <hi>My Dear, you muſt not ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pect any kind careſſes from me to night; for I am ſo weary that I cannot ſtir.</hi> This cauſed his Wife to curſe in her heart thoſe that had invented the poſt. A few dayes after walking with his Wife in the yard, he ſpied the Cock ſitting in the Sun aſleep by the Henns, without following them. Then he asked his Wife what made the Cock ſo dull and ſleepy by his Hens? <hi>I do not know, Husband,</hi> ſaid ſhe, <hi>unleſs he hath ridden poſt.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="200" type="jest">
               <pb n="76" facs="tcp:51789:41"/>
               <head>200.</head>
               <p>A Captain having loſt one eye by a Musket ſhot in the late Wars, the other became diſtempered ever after, and often ran with water. This made a friend of his ask him one day, Why that eye that was well, wept ſo much? <hi>Alas,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>how ſhould it do otherwiſe, having loſt its one<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly brother.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="201" type="jest">
               <head>201.</head>
               <p>One told his friend merrily he was be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>witcht, for as much as his head was all in one lump: <hi>And you my friend,</hi> replied the other, <hi>I am afraid are mad; for your heart is not on the right ſide.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="202" type="jest">
               <head>202.</head>
               <p>A Lady going to viſit a Gentlewoman of her acquaintance, took her Maid a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>long with her, which was very ſimple and ignorant; and it happen'd, as they came away, that in ſtraining comple<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, there eſcaped a fart; not a thun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dering one, but a Lady's fart; born be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore its time. At this accident ſhe became very much aſhamed, and to excuſe her ſelf, ſhe put it upon the Maid, ſaying, <hi>Get you hence you ſtinking ſlut.</hi> The Maid being wrongfully accuſed, as all the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany knew, went about to excuſe her
<pb n="77" facs="tcp:51789:41"/>
ſelf: but her Miſtriſs perſiſting, made her hold her tongue; and ſo took leave of the company. Afterwards when ſhe was out and alone with her Maid, ſhe ſaid, <hi>How now impudence, how durſt you contradict me? Did you not ſee I did it to ſave my cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dit before the company? And that it would have been better, they ſhould have thought it had been you, than I.</hi> The Maid begg'd pardon, ſaying, She did not think in the leaſt of that. <hi>Go, go, you are a beaſt,</hi> ſaid her Miſtriſs, <hi>and by your dulneſs make me ſuffer ſhame.</hi> Whereupon the poor inno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cent Maid, to repair her fault, went back privately to the Houſe whence they came, and entred into the Room where all the Company was, laughing ſtill at the pleaſant Diſpute between the Lady and her Maid: Then making a great reve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rence, ſhe ſaid aloud, <hi>Gentlemen and La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dies, I declare freely, that the fart which was let here juſt now, I take upon my ſelf.</hi> Which cauſed the Company to redouble their laughter at the ſimplicity of the Maid.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="203" type="jest">
               <head>203.</head>
               <p>Some unlucky Lads in the Univerſity, bearing a ſpight to the Dean for his ſeve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity towards them, went ſecretly one
<pb n="78" facs="tcp:51789:42"/>
night and daubed the Rails of his Stair-Caſe. The Dean coming down in the dark, foul'd his hands in the dung; at which much inra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged, he reſolved to make examination a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongſt all thoſe that were moſt likely and ſuſpected to do it: but chiefly he ſent for one and laid it on him, as being moſt ſuſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted to be the Author. This the Lad ut<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terly denies, but the Dean and the Fel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lows being ſtill more urgent upon him to confeſs the matter; <hi>Truly,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>I did it not, but if you pleaſe, I ſhall tell you who had a hand in it.</hi> Here the Dean thought to have found the truth, and thereupon asked him whoſe? <hi>Your Worſhips Sr,</hi> ſaid the Lad; which cauſed him to be diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſs'd with great applauſe for his in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>genuity.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="204" type="jest">
               <head>204.</head>
               <p>A Clown bringing a Letter to a Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tlemans Houſe, delivered it in haſte to a a great Baboon that ſtood at the Door in a Scarlet laced Coat; the Baboon ſoon tears the Letter to pieces. The Gentleman having heard of the buſineſs, when he met the Countreyman next, began to ſcold at him bitterly for not bringing him the Letter. <hi>I will aſſure you,</hi> replied the Peaſant, <hi>I delivered it to your Son at the
<pb n="79" facs="tcp:51789:42"/>
Door. My Son,</hi> ſays the Gentleman, <hi>you Fool, 'twas a Baboon. Truly,</hi> an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwered he, <hi>I thought it was your Son, he was ſo like you.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="205" type="jest">
               <head>205</head>
               <p>A certain Apothecary in <hi>London,</hi> ſee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing a young Ruſtick Fellow that look'd ſomewhat ſimply on the matter; with a Hare on a ſtick, which he was carrying to market to ſell; ſaid to his Companions, <hi>Sirs, 'Twill be worth our while to get this Peaſants Hare from him by ſome pleaſant ſtratagem, and that ſhall be this, I will ride up before, and make him believe that it is a Cat which he carries, and will be judg'd by you.</hi> Thus he accoſts the Fel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low, ſaying, <hi>Friend how doth your Wife, whither carry you that Cat? How,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>what do you take this Hare for a Cat? A Hare,</hi> ſaid the Gentleman, laughing, <hi>why 'tis a Cat, thou Fool, canſt not thou diſtin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guiſh between a Hare and a Cat? I will lay thee the price of a good Hare, that 'tis no other then a Cat; and we will be judged by thoſe Gentlemen that ride by yonder tree.</hi> The Peaſant recollecting himſelf, and truſting his eye-ſight, laid the Wager; but was ſoon daunted, when he ſaw him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf condemned by his Judges: who made
<pb n="80" facs="tcp:51789:43"/>
him believe that 'twas a Cat; and ſo ſent him home empty handed, whileſt they went and eat the Hare, not without great mirth and pleaſure, conſidering the ſim<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plicity of the Clown: whoſe Wife as ſoon as he came home, asked him what he had got for the Hare? <hi>You fool,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>'twas a Cat; Lord that you and I ſhould be ſo deceived.</hi> His Wife thought him mad, and he call'd her fool, that at laſt they contended ſo much, that the Neighbours came in to part them; and underſtanding the matter, made them friends again, by ſhewing plainly, that 'twas a trick of the Apothecary. His Wife reſolving to be revenged, went not long after and filled a little Barrel with Turds, and put the thick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs of three fingers of Honey on the top, which ſhe carried to the Apothecary, ask<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing if he would buy her Honey, which ſhe would ſell him very cheap: the gree<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy Apothecary took it at an under rate, and the woman went away rejoycing ſhe had returned cheat for cheat ſo effectually. Not long after the matter being diſcover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, the Apothecary became even to this day, a cauſe of mirth and laughter to as many as knew the matter: every one ask<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing him whether the Cat that ate the Hare, had ſhit the Honey.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="jest">
               <pb n="81" facs="tcp:51789:43"/>
               <head>2<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>6.</head>
               <p>A Souldier, a merry fellow, finding a Louſe one day on his ſleeve, walking to and fro to take the Air, took him up by the back between his fingers, and ſaid, <hi>I proteſt if I catch you again out of your quarters, you ſhall die;</hi> and ſo put him in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to his Collar.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="207" type="jest">
               <head>207.</head>
               <p>A Countrey Farmer coming up to the <hi>Temple,</hi> to enquire for his Son, whom he had ſent thither to ſtudy the Law, found in a Note that was left in the Key hole, <hi>I am gone to the Devil. Ah,</hi> ſaid his Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, <hi>my dear Child, have I brought thee up ſo tenderly, to come to this?</hi> and began to take it ſo heavily, ſuppoſing the Law had brought him to the Devil before his time.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="208" type="jest">
               <head>208.</head>
               <p>A Maid being to dreſs a Rabbet for her Maſters Supper, being newly come to Town, partly out of ignorance, partly out of haſte, ſent it to the Table with the ears on the head: this made the Compa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny laugh ſo, that her Maſter could not find in his heart to be angry<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> but onely ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ſhed her that ſhe ſhould not uſe to ſend up the ears. Not long after there
<pb n="82" facs="tcp:51789:44"/>
was a Pig to be ſent to Table, and remem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bring her Maſters charge, ſhe eat up the two ears.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="209" type="jest">
               <head>209.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Alphonſus</hi> King of <hi>Naples,</hi> had in his Court a Fool, which uſed to write down in a Book all the Follies of the great men of his time, that were at Court. The King one day, having a Moor in his Hou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhold, he ſent him to the <hi>Levant</hi> to buy Horſes with Ten thouſand Ducats. This the Fool marked in his Book, eſteeming it a pure folly. In ſhort time after, the King as he uſed to do, when he had a mind to be merry, called for the Book, and found at laſt his own name, with the Story of the Ten thouſand Ducats. The King being ſomewhat moved, asked the reaſon why his name was there? <hi>Becauſe,</hi> ſaid the Jeſter, <hi>you have committed a piece of folly, to give your money to one you are never like to ſee again. But if he come a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gain,</hi> anſwered the King, <hi>and bring me the Horſes, what folly is that in me?</hi> Then replied the Fool, <hi>If he ever come again, I will blot out your name, and put in his, th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> is ſo fooliſh to return with your money.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="210" type="jest">
               <pb n="83" facs="tcp:51789:44"/>
               <head>210.</head>
               <p>An Engliſh Merchant trading at <hi>Am<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſterdam,</hi> was to ſell a thouſand pounds worth of Gloves to certain Jews, and had agreed upon the price: but the Jews re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>canting of the bargain, when they brought their money would have but half. <hi>Well,</hi> ſaid the Engliſh Merchant, <hi>then you muſt give me a little time to ſort them, and you ſhall have half;</hi> ſo he commanded his men to put all the right-handed ones in one parcel, and the left in another: then when the Jews came, he bid them take their choice, which being made, and the money paid, they began to pack them up; but perceiving at laſt they were all for one hand, they were forced to come and buy the reſt at the Merchants rate.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="211" type="jest">
               <head>211.</head>
               <p>A poor Yorkſhire man bringing up his Son to the Univerſity, was told he might have very good lodging when he came there, at the Cardinals Cap <hi>Yes but,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>will it not make my Son a Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>piſt?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="212" type="jest">
               <head>212.</head>
               <p>The ſame man being come to the Uni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſity with his Son, as they were both
<pb n="84" facs="tcp:51789:45"/>
drinking in the Kitchin at their Inn, the youth eſpied a long Kettle amongſt the reſt, and knowing this was the place where he was to get his Learning, <hi>Pray father,</hi> ſays he, <hi>what is that Kettle for. Why,</hi> ſaid his Father, <hi>'tis ſuch a one as we never had in all our generation; but I ſuppoſe it is, that when they would have two ſeveral broths, they put fiſh in one end, and fleſh i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> the other.</hi> The boy hearing this, makes anſwer to his father, <hi>O the Devil <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> you.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="213" type="jest">
               <head>213.</head>
               <p>'Tis reported of King <hi>James,</hi> that when a Gentleman made as though he took a Louſe off his Arm, he gave him Twenty pounds, ſaying it was a Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man's companion. Whereupon, to make the King merry, he ſaid, <hi>That he would maintain a Louſe to be the nimbleſt and the ſloweſt of all Animals; the ſtrongeſt and the weakeſt; the worſt and the beſt. The nimbleſt,</hi> ſays he, <hi>becauſe let me go never ſo faſt<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> it never deſerts me; the ſloweſt, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe if I will pull it out of my head and lay it down, it can never overtake me; the ſtrongeſt, becauſe if a houſe fall on me, yet 'tis ten to one if the Louſe be kill'd and knock'd in the head; the weakeſt, becauſe I
<pb n="85" facs="tcp:51789:45"/>
can kill it with my Thumb; the worſt com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>panion, becauſe it alwayes preys upon me; and the beſt, becauſe it alwayes accompanies me in my adverſity.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="214" type="jest">
               <head>214.</head>
               <p>A ſimple Fellow walking in the Fields alone, came at laſt to a Ditch, and ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king a pauſe, <hi>Now Robin,</hi> ſaid he to him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf, <hi>what do'ſt think, canſt thou leap over this Ditch or no? In faith,</hi> replied he to himſelf, <hi>I cannot tell; but if thou wilt</hi> Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bin, <hi>I will lay thee a Crown I do. A match.</hi> And ſo he prepar'd himſelf to leap, and taking a good run and the advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tage of the Bank, he leaped quite o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver. <hi>Ah boys,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>there's your Crown, But now,</hi> Robin, <hi>wilt thou lay another, that thou canſt leap back? Faith that's very difficult, nevertheleſs hang it, I do.</hi> Then taking a good run, he leaps juſt into the middle up to the waſte in mire and water; but crawling out on the other ſide, <hi>Hang it,</hi> ſays he, <hi>I don't much care, I have neither won nor loſt.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="215" type="jest">
               <head>215.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Ralph Amner,</hi> the great Bull-maker of <hi>Windſor,</hi> tumbling one day over a Form, <hi>A pox on it,</hi> ſays he, <hi>I have burnt my ſhins.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="216" type="jest">
               <pb n="86" facs="tcp:51789:46"/>
               <head>216.</head>
               <p>A Roguiſh Butcher told a Fool he would give him a farthing to leap into the kennel, which was pretty broad after the new-fallen rain; ſo the Fool hopt in, firſt with one foot, but the Butcher would have him leap in with both; then he hops in with the other, yet was very loath to leap in with both. The Butcher ſtill urg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing him, at laſt he leaps in with both, and then would have his farthing: But the Butcher ſaid he would give him none. <hi>I thought ſo at firſt,</hi> ſays he, and ſo goes his way.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="217" type="jest">
               <head>217.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Tom</hi> the Barber ſeeing his Neighbour cut down a Pear Tree, deſired him to let him have ſome of it; <hi>Why what uſe would you put it to?</hi> ſaid he. <hi>I would,</hi> replied he, <hi>onely make a few Box Combs.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="218" type="jest">
               <head>218.</head>
               <p>A Lawyer and a Divine being merry together, the former to jeer the latter, ſaid, <hi>I heard a Prieſt ſay one Sunday in his Sermon, inſtead of</hi> Jonas <hi>was three dayes and three nights in the Whales Belly, that he was three dayes and three nights in a Quailes Belly. And I,</hi> ſaid the Divine, <hi>heard one ſay once Inſtead of the Devil was
<pb n="87" facs="tcp:51789:46"/>
a Liar from the beginning, the Devil was a Lawyer from the beginning.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="219" type="jest">
               <head>219.</head>
               <p>One related in a Coffee-houſe, how he had ſeen in <hi>Turkey</hi> a Hall thirty miles <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ong, and a Table therein ſix and thirty; which a young careleſs Gallant taking for truth, related in the next Company he met: where all laughed very much at the improbability, that a Table could be long<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er than the place where it ſtood; and the Gentleman was much aſhamed. The nex<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> time therefore he met the perſon of whom he heard the Story, he began to quarrel with him, for having offered to impoſe ſuch Lies and Fables, as that was concern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Table, on Gentlemen, that expe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted to hear nothing from him but the truth. <hi>Why what untruth do you find in my relation?</hi> ſaid he. <hi>What?</hi> replied the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther; <hi>Can any thing be more againſt reaſon, than that a Table ſhould be ſix and thirty miles long, and the Room where it ſtands but thirty? Alas Sir,</hi> replied the other, <hi>you did not take all the ſtory; for it turn'd in four miles at each end.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="220" type="jest">
               <head>220.</head>
               <p>Two Fools waſhing their feet in a Brook, had ſo entangled their feet, that <pb n="88" facs="tcp:51789:47"/>
they knew not which was which; one would have this, the other thought 'twas his, and they began to quarrel; but a Paſſenger ſeeing the ſimple contenti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, ſtruck them over their backs with his ſtick, and fear ſoon made them find their legs.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="221" type="jest">
               <head>221.</head>
               <p>A Countrey Carter coming through <hi>London</hi> Streets with his Hobnail'd Shoes in a ſlippery place, his heels flew up, and an Apprentice ſtanding in his <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>hop, ſaid to him, <hi>How now friend, you ſee our City ſtones are very proud, they ſcorn that a Bum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kin ſhould tread up<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>n them.</hi> To which he replied, <hi>As proud as they are, I made them kiſs mine Arſe.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="222" type="jest">
               <head>222.</head>
               <p>When a witty Gentleman heard, how a certain Impropriator made nothing to devour Churches, <hi>Alas,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>tis pity ſo bad a Liver ſhould have ſo good a Sto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mach.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="223" type="jest">
               <head>223.</head>
               <p>A Clown coming to <hi>London,</hi> read on a Sign-poſt, <hi>Here are Horſes to be let</hi> 1661. <hi>Cuds life,</hi> ſays he, <hi>if there are ſo many Horſes in one Inn, how many are there in all the City?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="224" type="jest">
               <pb n="89" facs="tcp:51789:47"/>
               <head>224.</head>
               <p>Amongſt a company of good fellows, one thinking to impoſe on the reſt, who were poor Seamen, told very ſoberly for a truth, That as two Gentlemen were fighting, one loſt his thumb in the fray, which a Chirurgeon paſſing by accidental<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, took up and put in his Pocket: This Chirurgeon meeting the Gentleman two moneths afterwards, and hearing him complain for the loſs of his thumb, told him for ſo much money he would ſet it on as faſt as ever; and did it ſo perfectly, that no one could tell that ever it had been cut off. <hi>And I doubt not,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>but if the man were living, I would have his hand to ſhew for it.</hi> One of the Seamen, who had liſtned all the while, and was too under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding, to be impoſed upon ſo groſly, ſaid, <hi>I had a thing happened to me once in my travels much like to this; which was, Travelling into the Countrey of the Canni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bals, with a friend of mine, I chanced to loſe him one day, and running to and fro to ſeek him, I ſaw at laſt a company of Canni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bals feeding on him; this misfortune made me very penſive, but conſidering no time was to be delay'd, I went privily and ſprinkled a powder that I had into their drink; and
<pb n="90" facs="tcp:51789:48"/>
they had no ſooner drank it, but they pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſently were drunk, and diſgorged their Sto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>machs of what they had eaten, and fell a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſleep: then ſeeing my ſelf pretty ſecure, ſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> had time to gather up the miſerable morſels of my friend, then placing them together, I powred ſome of the ſame powder on them, and reſtored him to life, and his perfect ſhape; and if he were yet alive, he himſelf would witneſs what I have told you. 'Ti<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> very ſtrange and improbable,</hi> quoth the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, <hi>that after your friend was not onely dead, but part of him ſwallowed down, and then vomited up again; that thoſe parts <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> chewed and half digeſted, ſhould ſtick to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether and become the ſame man. Oh Sir,</hi> ſaid the Seaman, <hi>you may eaſily imagi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> that, if you do but remember the thumb, the thumb.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="225" type="jest">
               <head>225.</head>
               <p>Two perſons quarrelling together, one ſtruck the other, but company coming between, hindered the fray at that time; nevertheleſs he that received the blow, threatned the other that he ſhould never eſcape ſo; and according to his word, the next time he had opportunity, which was a day or two after, he hit him over the mouth: the other in cool blood, and
<pb n="91" facs="tcp:51789:48"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ot willing to quarrel, was willing to paſs <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> away with a Jeſt. <hi>What,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ot one touch you, but you muſt hit one in the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>eth of it.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="226" type="jest">
               <head>226.</head>
               <p>A little boy ſitting with his Grandmo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>her by the fire in the winter time, when <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>e lifted up her Coats to warm her knees, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>pied ſomething between her legs; and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ould fain know what it was. <hi>It is,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>a Rabbet skin, that your Mother <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>rought me from Market. What and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ve you burnt a hole in it, Granny?</hi> ſaid <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>e.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="227" type="jest">
               <head>227.</head>
               <p>Some women talking of Cuckolds; one was ſo ſimple as to ask where their horns <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ew? another ſeeing her ignorance, ſaid, <hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>n the nape of the neck. Truly I thought ſo,</hi> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>aid ſhe, <hi>my Husband wears out his bands <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> much behind.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="228" type="jest">
               <head>228.</head>
               <p>The good man being out of Town, is neighbour brought home a pair of Pan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>iers he had borrowed, and lay with his wife in thanks; but he coming home un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>expectedly that night, diſturbed their kind embraces, and forced his wife for <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>aſte, to hide her friend in one of the Pan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niers,
<pb n="92" facs="tcp:51789:49"/>
as it was made faſt to a Croſs-bea<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> in the Room. The good man, being little in drink, as ſoon as he came in he would have a Candle; his wife fearin<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> this would diſcover her friend, was ver<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> much againſt it: but forced by the threa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> of her husband, at laſt ſhe light one and deſired him with kind ſpeeches an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> embraces to make haſte to bed; this kind<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>neſs ſo inflamed her husband, that <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> would fain be at her, even before he w<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> undreſſed: and when at laſt ſhe had help<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ed him to bed with great diligence, th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> her neighbour might not be ſeen whe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> he was ſitting with one leg in one Panni<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>er, the other in the other, croſs the Beam<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Her husband ſaid, <hi>Sweetheart, I hav<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> been married to thee theſe two years, an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> yet never ſaw what I had to do with; no<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> I am reſolved to view what hitherto I onely felt.</hi> So as he was looking on it earneſt<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ly with the Candle, and viewing it well the fellow on the Beam, that had neve<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> ſeen one before, leaned and leaned ſtill farther and farther, to get a ſight of it till at laſt he fell down Panniers and al<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> The good man, much affrighted, cry'd aloud, <hi>Who is there?</hi> to which the othe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> replied, <hi>'Tis I neighbour, am come t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <pb n="93" facs="tcp:51789:49"/>
bring you home your Panniers. A pox on <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ou,</hi> ſays he again, <hi>you need not have brought <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>hem home in ſuch haſte.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="229" type="jest">
               <head>229.</head>
               <p>One Citizen in a ſcoffing manner call'd <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>is neighbour <hi>Nicumpoope,</hi> and the other <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>aking it for ſome very ſhamful and op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>robrious name, reſolved not to put it <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>p, but quarrels with him. <hi>Why, I'll <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ay you forty ſhillings,</hi> ſaid the other, <hi>you <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>re;</hi> and ſuch a one ſhall be Judge be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ween us. The Wager being laid in that perſons hands, he ſends for the mans wife <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>o know whether he were a <hi>Nicumpoope</hi> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>or no. The Wife being come, <hi>Good wo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man;</hi> ſaid the Judge, <hi>you muſt here ſpeak and confeſs the truth for your husbands good, whether ever he ſaw your commodity <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>r no? Yes truly Sir, that he did,</hi> ſaid ſhe, <hi>this very morning, and kiſs'd it too.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="230" type="jest">
               <head>230.</head>
               <p>A covetous Gentleman, and one of no great wiſdom, whom avarice had bereft of right underſtanding, hearing his Stew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ards ſays, he had killed him a Bullock a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt the Holy-days; <hi>What,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>do you mean to undo me by ſuch extravagant expences; I will have but half a one kill'd at a time.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="231" type="jest">
               <pb n="94" facs="tcp:51789:50"/>
               <head>231.</head>
               <p>A Cheat and a Pick-Pocket play'd toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther at Dice, and ſtill as the Cheat won, the other pick'd his Pocket. At laſt ſaid the Pick-pocket, ſeeing he could win no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing by the Dice: <hi>Sir, you cheat me con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foundedly.</hi> The other feeling his Pocket empty, ſaid, <hi>And you have pick'd my pocket damnably.</hi> So every man to his own Trade.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="232" type="jest">
               <head>232.</head>
               <p>Two Welſh Gentlemen travelling, knockt very late at an Inn-keepers door, <hi>Who is there?</hi> cry'd the Hoſt. <hi>Some Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tlemen,</hi> ſaid they, <hi>that are benighted, and deſire lodging. How many?</hi> ſaid the Hoſt again. <hi>Why here are,</hi> ſaid one of them, <hi>John ap Rice ap Jones ap Hugh, and Ni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cholas ap Steven ap Giles ap Davy. Th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap> Gentlemen all good night,</hi> ſaid the Inn-keeper, <hi>I could have provided a bed or two; but cannot lodge ſuch a company.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="233" type="jest">
               <head>233.</head>
               <p>A Woman whoſe Husband had but one eye, hoping he could not ſee all her faults, kept great familiarity with a friend; but her Husband coming home one night unexpectedly, when they were both together, ſurprized and ignorant
<pb n="95" facs="tcp:51789:50"/>
what was beſt to be done, ſhe ran in great <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>aſte to the door, with a candle in her <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>and, ſayng, Husband I fell in a ſlumber <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>uſt now by the fire, and I dream'd you <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ould ſee with your other eye, and can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not beat it out of my mind; pray let me cover the other eye with my hand and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ry if you can perceive ought. By this witty ſtratagem ſhe gave time enough to her friend to convey himſelf out of the way, and to eſcape her Husband.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="234" type="jest">
               <head>234.</head>
               <p>A witty, though unfortunate fellow, ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving try'd all Trades, but thriving by none, took the Pot for his laſt refuge, and ſet up an Alehouſe, with the Sign of the Shirt; writing under it; <hi>This is my laſt Shift:</hi> which brought him much compa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny and much profit.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="235" type="jest">
               <head>235.</head>
               <p>Another, when he could not get a Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cence to ſell Ale, by reaſon of his pover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty; nevertheleſs brew'd good ſtrong Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quor: and if any one call'd for Ale, <hi>Truly Ale have I none,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>but I have what's as good;</hi> bringing a Pot of his own brewing. By which ingenious device he ſoon got money enough to buy a Licence.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="236" type="jest">
               <pb n="96" facs="tcp:51789:51"/>
               <head>236.</head>
               <p>A Frenchman and his wife lodging at an Engliſhman's houſe, both ſo perfect children of their own Countreys, that neither underſtood each other; it ſo fell out, that the Frenchman's wife cry'd out in the night, and he ran up ſtairs to call a Midwife which lay over him; this being done, he ran down to acquaint his Landlord and Landlady with it; where ſtanding by their Bed-ſide ſhivering, for it was in the depth of Winter. His Land-lady pitying him, ſaid to her husband, <hi>Pray husband, ſince the weather is ſo bit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter cold, and you are here in bed with me, that you need fear nothing; and the bed is large enough, let Monſieur come and lie down with us till day light.</hi> So the French<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man was permitted to lie down on the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther ſide of the woman. Now by that time, the good man having been weari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed by his daily labour, was fallen aſleep again, the Snake began to grow warm, and crawl'd up upon the woman's belly. The motion of the bed awaking her huſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>band, he calls out, <hi>Wife what do you do with the Frenchman, what do you do? Why what would you have me do?</hi> ſaid ſhe, <hi>If I ſhould ſpeak to him, you know
<pb n="97" facs="tcp:51789:51"/>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>he underſtands not one word of Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſh.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="237" type="jest">
               <head>237.</head>
               <p>A Preacher took his Text thus, <hi>O ye fools, when will ye underſtand. Now my Text,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>is the Voice of the Crier O <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>e, and fools, my beloved, are ſo nearly joyn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed to ye, that I cannot ſeparate fools from ye, nor ye from fools.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="238" type="jest">
               <head>238.</head>
               <p>Another took his Text, <hi>Have patience with me, and I will pay you all;</hi> and ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving largely and learnedly treated of the noble Vertue of Patience, eſpecially in forbearing our Debtors here; <hi>But of the reſt,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>when God ſhall enable me.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="239" type="jest">
               <head>239.</head>
               <p>A certain Vicar, whom the Pariſhio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners had denied his full allowance, reſol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved if it were poſſible, to give them a rub, and coming one morning to that place in the Pſalms, where it is ſaid, <hi>Man without underſtanding, is like to the beast that periſhes;</hi> he read thus, <hi>Man without underſtanding, is like the beſt in the Pariſh.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="240" type="jest">
               <head>240.</head>
               <p>One taking a flie out of a Glaſs, after he had drank, put it in again very care<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully;
<pb n="98" facs="tcp:51789:52"/>
and being asked the reaſon? <hi>Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>I do not know but ſome i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> this company may love it ſo.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="241" type="jest">
               <head>241.</head>
               <p>A prating Lawyer, in his Cups main<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained, that one day was not to be kept more than another; and if any one ſneez<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>d, to cry <hi>God ſave you,</hi> to him, was witch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>craft. At laſt he happened himſelf to ſneeze, whereat one in the room ſaid, <hi>Hold faſt behind,</hi> twice or thrice. This ſo offended the Lawyer, that he began to rebuke him that ſaid it. <hi>Why,</hi> replied the other, <hi>truly I would have ſaid God bleſs your Worſhip, but that I feared you ſhould take me for a Wizard.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="242" type="jest">
               <head>242.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman reprehended a certain Lawyer for tarrying ſo long in the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trey from his wife, ſaying, That in his abſence, ſhe might want due Benevo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lence. <hi>Why Sir,</hi> replied the Lawyer, <hi>I ſhall give it her in full meaſure, when I re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turn; and put the Caſe any one owed you a hundred pounds, whether had you rather have it all together, or ſhilling by ſhilling? That is very true indeed,</hi> replied the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, <hi>one would rather have ones money all together; yet it would vex you if your
<pb n="99" facs="tcp:51789:52"/>
wife in your abſence ſhould want a ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="243" type="jest">
               <head>243.</head>
               <p>When the Souldiers in a Camp began to be very lowſie, and complained to to their Captain they were not able to endure them. <hi>Turn your ſhirts,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>and ſhake them, and the lice will have a dayes march at leaſt, before they can come to your skin.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="244" type="jest">
               <head>244.</head>
               <p>One told a <hi>London</hi> Hector, he won<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred he did not fear to be ſo much in debt? <hi>Damn you,</hi> ſays he, <hi>am I in debt? I owe no man a farthing. Why Sir,</hi> repli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed the other again, <hi>you know well enough, that Peruque, thoſe Cloaths, thoſe Stock<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings and Shoes, that Hat, and that Muff are not yet paid for. Yes,</hi> ſays he, <hi>that's true; but he onely owes, that intends to pay.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="245" type="jest">
               <head>245.</head>
               <p>A <hi>London</hi> Taylor, true but for lying, honeſt but for ſtealing, fell ſuddenly very ſick, and when his friends began to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpair of his recovery, and that he thought himſelf he ſhould die, his Conſcience be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gan to prick him, and to bring into his imagination all his former ſins; then did
<pb n="100" facs="tcp:51789:53"/>
he think he ſaw before him all the Fiends of Hell diſplaying ſundry colours of thoſe Silks he had at ſeveral times ſtoln; this ſo terrified him, that after he grew well, he bought him a Bible, went to Church, and ſhewed great reformation; nay the very meat that was to be eat on Sunday, he would have dreſt on Saturday; alſo leaſt the cuſtom and frequent uſe he had of ſtealing, ſhould at any time make him for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>get his zeal, he gave his Journeyman a ſpecial charge to put the apparition in his mind, when ever he ſaw him ſtealing any thing. Not long af<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>er, when a Doctor of Phyſick ſent him ſome Velvet to make him a Goat, and he well knowing how much would ſerve, ſnips off half a yard: but his man eſpying it, ſaid, <hi>O Maſter, Maſter, remember the Viſion. Yes, yes,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>I do remember the Viſion, but there was not one piece of ſuch Silk in any part of it.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="246" type="jest">
               <head>246.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman that took great delight in Hunting, came haſtily one day into his Friends Chamber, as he was employed a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout ſome other buſineſs, asking him if he would go find a Hare? <hi>Piſh,</hi> ſaid the other, <hi>let me alone, let them go find Hares that have loſt them.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="247" type="jest">
               <pb n="101" facs="tcp:51789:53"/>
               <head>247.</head>
               <p>One ſending a Pair of Gloves to his Lady for a New-years Gift, writ on the Paper theſe two witty Verſes,
<q>
                     <l>If that from <hi>Glove</hi> you take the Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter <hi>G,</hi>
                     </l>
                     <l>Then <hi>Glove</hi> is <hi>Love,</hi> and that I ſend to thee.</l>
                  </q>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="248" type="jest">
               <head>248.</head>
               <p>A witty Fellow in a company, when the whole diſcourſe was of the Female Sex, ſaid, <hi>That Women were born in</hi> Wiltſhire, <hi>brought up in</hi> Cumberland, <hi>led their lives in</hi> Bedfordſhire, <hi>brought their husbands to</hi> Buckinghamſhire, <hi>and died in</hi> Shrews<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bury.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="249" type="jest">
               <head>249.</head>
               <p>When Mr. <hi>Kitchin</hi> a great Braſier in <hi>London,</hi> died, <hi>Cuds life,</hi> ſays one, <hi>will Death have his Kitchin un<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> ground.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="250" type="jest">
               <head>250.</head>
               <p>A Welchman lying in an Alehou<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>, h<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>d run up a great deal for Cheeſe, his Hoſteſs therefore demanding a Shilling; <hi>How the Devil cuds ſplutter an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> nails can that be?</hi> ſaid he. <hi>Why look here,</hi> ſaid ſhe, point<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the ſcore behind the door. <hi>Ah,
<pb n="102" facs="tcp:51789:54"/>
thae's brave indeed,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>what doth her think her does not know Chalk from Cheeſe.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="251" type="jest">
               <head>251.</head>
               <p>Another as he travelled on the Road, and came to his Inn, he found nothing elſe ready but Plaice, ſo he would have two; and the Hoſt dreſſed them and ſent them up: then having eat all on the black ſide, he found himſelf not ſatisfied, and call'd for two more. The man ſeeing his ſimplicity, took away the Diſh, turn'd the Plaice, and ſerved them up with a lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle new Butter. <hi>Cuds life,</hi> ſays our <hi>Taf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fy, hath he black Plaice and white Plaice too?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="252" type="jest">
               <head>252.</head>
               <p>A Baron and a Knight walking toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther on a Green, a Crow lighted on a Rail by them, making a great noiſe. <hi>I believe,</hi> ſays the Baron, <hi>Sir Knight, this Bird ſaluteth you. Nay rather,</hi> ſaid the Knight, <hi>tis to ſome Lord he makes ſuch low obeyſance.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="253" type="jest">
               <head>253.</head>
               <p>One meeting <hi>Bonner,</hi> that had been once Biſhop of <hi>London,</hi> ſaid, <hi>Good mor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>row Biſhop</hi> quondam; whereupon he re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plied preſently, <hi>Adieu Knave</hi> ſemper.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="254" type="jest">
               <pb n="103" facs="tcp:51789:54"/>
               <head>254.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Hugh Peters</hi> preaching of Faith and Hope, after a long and tedious diſcourſe, forgot Charity; for he call'd out to a wo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man, that was talking with her Neigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bour, to leave babling. <hi>Beſhrew thy heart,</hi> ſaid ſhe, <hi>who babbles moſt thou or I?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="255" type="jest">
               <head>255.</head>
               <p>The ſame man having newly hopt from the Stall to the Pulpit, inſtead of the Prieſt <hi>offered up a pair of Doves for a peace offering,</hi> read, <hi>he offered up a pair of Gloves and a piece of fringe.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="256" type="jest">
               <head>256.</head>
               <p>'Tis ſaid alſo of another of thoſe fine Preachers in his days, that he thought himſelf very learned and a good Divine, when he ſaid thus in his Sermon, <hi>Para<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diſe is become a pair of dice, and all houſes turn Alehouſes; but 'twas not ſo in the dayes of Noah, ah no.</hi> Another time he took this for his Text, <hi>My Bed is green,</hi> one<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly to ſhew this fancy, <hi>Typical my, Topi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cal Bed, and Tropical green; So beloved you ſee how it stands, Typical my, Topical Bed, Tropical green; Typical, Topical, Tro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pical, my Bed is green.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="257" type="jest">
               <pb n="104" facs="tcp:51789:55"/>
               <head>257.</head>
               <p>When <hi>Tom Holland</hi> quartering in <hi>Fleet-ſtreet,</hi> had raiſed his Landlady's Maids Belly, whoſe name was <hi>Nell Cotton,</hi> 'twas wittily ſaid by an ingenious perſon, <hi>That he gave her a yard of</hi> Holland, <hi>ſhe gave him an ell of</hi> Cotton, <hi>and what harm was there in all that.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="258" type="jest">
               <head>258.</head>
               <p>Some boon Companions being merry at a Tavern, every one began to com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mend one ſort of Wine or other; one e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpecially ſtood up for Sack that 'twas a good Cordial, and would make one fat; <hi>Nay rather,</hi> ſays another, <hi>'twill make one lean. How ſo? <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>pon a Staffe.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="259" type="jest">
               <head>259.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman meeting his friend, who had a very pretty Lacquey, ask'd him where he was? <hi>Alas Sir,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>death hath ſent him on an errand. And what is become of your Nag Sir, you came up on? Why he is foundred. Why then,</hi> replied the other, <hi>he hath ſerved you right, to make you go on foot, ſince you made him lame.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="260" type="jest">
               <head>260</head>
               <p>One bid his Shoe-maker make one of his Boots bigger than the other, and when
<pb n="105" facs="tcp:51789:55"/>
he brought them home, <hi>A pox on you for a Rogue,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>I bid you make one big<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger, and you have made one leſs.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="261" type="jest">
               <head>261.</head>
               <p>The ſame Bull-ſpeeker talking of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> ſaid, <hi>That truly the City was a gal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lant place, but the Air was very foggy, and a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>greed not with him; and he did really think, that had he lived there till this time, that he had died ſeven years ago.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="262" type="jest">
               <head>262.</head>
               <p>A diſcreet Gentleman being asked why he would not go, when his friend deſired him, to have a man that could counter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feit the Nightingale exactly? <hi>Becauſe,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>I have heard her, when ſhe ſung her ſelf.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="263" type="jest">
               <head>263.</head>
               <p>A Welſhman travelling with a Charge of Money behind him in his Cloakbag, was met by a Thief, who bid him to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liver his Money immediately; or elſe he would make that Piſtol, drawing one out of its Caſe, to bounce thorow him. <hi>What,</hi> ſaid the Welſhman, <hi>muſt that Piſtol pounch through her? Her had better give her mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney that is her Maſters, and ſpare her life that is her own.</hi> So the Thief without any reſiſtance, took his Cloak-bag. <hi>But pray
<pb n="106" facs="tcp:51789:56"/>
Sir,</hi> ſaid the Welſhman, <hi>ſince her hath her money, let her hear one pounce for it; for her never heard the pounce of a Cun.</hi> The Thief, ro ſatisfie him, diſcharged his Piſtol, which ecchoed in many places. <hi>Cuds ſplutter and nails,</hi> ſaid the Welſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man, <hi>'twas a gallant pounce, and there was many little pounces too; Pray let her have one more pounce, for 'tis a gallant thing.</hi> So the Thief let off his other Piſtol, at which the Welſhman ſeemed more plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed than before; and asked if he had no more pounces? <hi>No,</hi> ſaid the Thief, <hi>I have not one more.</hi> Then replied the Welſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man, that had long enough pleaded ig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>norance, <hi>Her has one Piſtol: and unleſs her give her her money, her ſhall make it pounce through her.</hi> And ſo forced the Thief to reſtore him his Cloak-bag a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gain.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="263" type="jest">
               <head>263.</head>
               <p>A certain bold woman came to <hi>Grati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>an</hi> the Emperour, and with much clamor complained to him of her Husband; to whom the Emperour mildly ſaid, <hi>Woman what are theſe things to me? Yea,</hi> ſaid ſhe, <hi>for he hath alſo ſpoken many things againſt thee.</hi> To which the Emperour anſwered, <hi>Woman what is that to thee?</hi> Which ſo
<pb n="107" facs="tcp:51789:56"/>
abaſhed the woman, that ſhe went away aſhamed.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="264" type="jest">
               <head>264.</head>
               <p>A Boy vapouring of his Game Cock, ſaid, <hi>It would die in the place. Nay,</hi> ſaid a Gentleman, ſtanding by, <hi>Give me a Cock that will live in the place.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="265" type="jest">
               <head>265.</head>
               <p>At the Battle of <hi>Newport,</hi> the Prince of <hi>Orange</hi> having the Spaniſh Army be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore him, and the Sea behind him; ſaid to his Souldiers, <hi>If you will live, you muſt chuſe one of theſe two things of neceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſity, either to eat thoſe Spanyards, or drink that Sea:</hi> which ſo encreaſed the Souldi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers appetite to war, that they eat up the Spaniards indeed, and got a noble Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctory.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="266" type="jest">
               <head>266.</head>
               <p>When amongſt many Articles exhibited to King <hi>Henry</hi> by the <hi>Iriſh</hi> againſt the Earl of <hi>Kildar,</hi> the laſt was, <hi>Finally, All</hi> Ireland <hi>cannot rule this Earl. Th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>n;</hi> quoth the King, <hi>The Earl ſhall rule all</hi> Ireland; and ſo made him his Deputy.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="267" type="jest">
               <head>267.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman being prickt for High Sheriff, who by reaſon of ſome indiſpoſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, deſired to get off from that Office,
<pb n="108" facs="tcp:51789:57"/>
his Wife enquiring into the matter, ask<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed a Gentleman concerning it. <hi>Alas Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dam,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>your husband is prickt by the King, and it cannot be altered. Why Sir,</hi> ſaid ſhe again, <hi>doth the Kings Prick al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wayes ſtand.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="268" type="jest">
               <head>268.</head>
               <p>About the year 1670, there was a no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>table Robber hanged at <hi>Tyburn,</hi> whoſe name was <hi>Braſs,</hi> whereupon a witty per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon ſaid, <hi>'Twas no wonder if ſo many Rob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beries were committed, ſince our walls were but clay, and our thieves of braſs.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="269" type="jest">
               <head>269.</head>
               <p>King <hi>John</hi> being perſwaded by a Cour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tier to untomb the bones of one, who in his life time had been his great enemy. <hi>O no,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>I would to God all my enemies were as honourably buried.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="270" type="jest">
               <head>270.</head>
               <p>Queen <hi>Elizabeth</hi> coming to a Free-School, where ſhe had an Oration ſpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken to her by one of the Boys; ſhe after<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards asked him how often he had been whipp'd? To which, he wittily anſwered with the words of <hi>Aeneas</hi> to Queen <hi>Dido,</hi>
                  <q>Infandum Regina jubes renovare dolorem.</q>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="271" type="jest">
               <pb n="109" facs="tcp:51789:57"/>
               <head>271.</head>
               <p>Another time having ſome Verſes made to her <hi>extempore,</hi> by a poor School-boy, and underſtanding his condition, ſhe ſaid, <hi>Make me ſome Verſes upon this, Pauper ubique jacet,</hi> to which he ſaid,
<q>
                     <l>In thalamis Regina tuis hac nocte jacerem,</l>
                     <l>Si verum hoc eſſet, pauper ubique jacet.</l>
                  </q>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="272" type="jest">
               <head>272.</head>
               <p>A Papiſt, as their uſual manner is, ask<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed a Proteſtant where his Religion was before <hi>Luther? Why in the Bible,</hi> an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwered he, <hi>where yours never was.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="273" type="jest">
               <head>273.</head>
               <p>Sir <hi>Walter Raleigh</hi> asking a favour of Queen <hi>Elizabeth,</hi> ſays the Queen, <hi>Sir</hi> Walter, <hi>when do you intend to leave off beg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ging? When your gracious Majeſty,</hi> reply'd he, <hi>ſhall leave off giving.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="274" type="jest">
               <head>274.</head>
               <p>When one asked his Friend to aſſiſt him in a baſe action, and was deny'd, <hi>What am I the better,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>for ſuch a friend, that denies me his help? And what am I the better,</hi> ſays the other, <hi>for a friend that demands ſuch unreaſonable things?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="275" type="jest">
               <pb n="110" facs="tcp:51789:58"/>
               <head>275.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>John Scot,</hi> famous through the whole world for his learning, being asked by a young Gallant that thought to have jeſted on him, as he ſat at Table, <hi>What dif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ference there was between</hi> Scot <hi>and a</hi> Sot? anſwered ſuddenly <hi>Menſa tantum,</hi> that is, the Tables breadth; for the other ſate juſt over againſt him.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="276" type="jest">
               <head>276.</head>
               <p>The ſame perſon being worthily enter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained by <hi>Charolus Calvus</hi> the French King, as he was once at Dinner with the King, there was a Diſh wherein were two great Fiſhes and a little one; the King having taſted it, ſent it down to <hi>Scot,</hi> to diſtribute it to two other Clerks that ſate by him, and were two tall proper per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons; wherefore <hi>John</hi> taking the Diſh, gave the little Fiſh to the other two, and kept the two great ones for himſelf. The King obſerving this diviſion, blamed him for not having dealt equally; but he pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved his diſtribution to be juſt, after this manner; <hi>Here,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>be two great ones and a little one,</hi> pointing to the two great Fiſhes and himſelf, who was but little of ſtature; <hi>and there is one little one and two greas ones,</hi> pointing to the little Fiſh and
<pb n="111" facs="tcp:51789:58"/>
the two tall Clerks; and what diſtributi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on can be more equal?</p>
            </div>
            <div n="277" type="jest">
               <head>277.</head>
               <p>A Scotchman preſented King <hi>James</hi> with a Turnip of an extraordinary and pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>digious ſize; which is a Root the Scotch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men love very much. The King pleaſed with the humor, gave him a hundred pounds, which another Courtier ſeeing, If the King, thought he, reward a Tur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nip giver ſo liberally, what will he do to him that offers a greater preſent? and thereupon preſents the King with a very excellent Race-horſe, wherefore the King turning to his Nobles, ſaid, <hi>What ſhall we give this man?</hi> and when all were ſilent, <hi>By my ſoul men,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>let us give him the Turnip.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="278" type="jest">
               <head>278.</head>
               <p>When <hi>Metellus Nepos</hi> asked <hi>Cicero</hi> the Roman Orator, in a jeering way, who was his Father? he reply'd, <hi>Thy Mother hath made that queſtion harder for thee to an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="279" type="jest">
               <head>279.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Marcus Livius</hi> the Roman, who was Governour of <hi>Tarentum,</hi> when <hi>Hannibal</hi> took it; being envious to ſee ſo much ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour done to <hi>Fabius Maximus,</hi> ſaid one
<pb n="112" facs="tcp:51789:59"/>
day openly in the Senate, That 'twas him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf, not <hi>Fabius Maximus,</hi> that was the cauſe of the retaking the City of <hi>Taren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tum, Fabius</hi> ſmiling to hear him, an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwered wittily, <hi>Indeed thou ſpeakeſt truth, for if thou hadſt not loſt it, I had never won it again.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="280" type="jest">
               <head>280.</head>
               <p>When Parſon <hi>Bull</hi> came to viſit the Chancellour <hi>Hide, Hide</hi> ſaid ſmiling, <hi>Bull where are your horns? Sir,</hi> replied he, <hi>they go alwayes with the Hide.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="281" type="jest">
               <head>281.</head>
               <p>Pope <hi>Benedict,</hi> when the Ambaſſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>dour of the Council of <hi>Conſtance,</hi> came to him, laying his hand on his breaſt, he ſaid, <hi>Hic eſt Arca Noae;</hi> to which they tartly, but truly reply'd, <hi>In Noah's Ark there were few men but many beaſts,</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="282" type="jest">
               <head>282.</head>
               <p>A blind man hired a lame man, that is, one that had but one leg, and the other a woodden one, to lead him up and down the Streets, the more to move the pity of the beholders; and as they travelled one day, the lame man ſaw an Oyſter lie in the way; wherefore ſtooping down to reach it, the other perceived he made a ſtop, and asked him what he took up? ſo
<pb n="113" facs="tcp:51789:59"/>
he told him, that he had found a lovely Oyſter: <hi>Give it me,</hi> ſaid the blind man. The other, <hi>By the right of fortune,</hi> ſaid, <hi>it was his,</hi> and would not deliver it. Not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding the blind man pleaded he was his Maſter. Then they reſolved to be judged by the next they met, which hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pened to be a ſubtil Lawyer; who after he underſtood the matter, and that theſe two fools muſt wrangle for ſo ſmall a mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, draws out his knife and opens the Oyſter, then eats it, and gives to each a ſhell.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="283" type="jest">
               <head>283.</head>
               <p>A Welſhman coming late to his Inn, went to bed in the dark, and being very dry, and finding a Bottle there on a Cup-boards head, he ſuppoſed it to be drink, and ſupp'd it off; which was indeed Quick-ſilver. In the morning when he felt the matter in the bed, for fear his Hoſteſs ſhould perceive he had beſhit it, he aroſe and departed before day.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="384" type="jest">
               <head>384.</head>
               <p>Another of the ſame Countrey, going in a dark night in <hi>London</hi> with his Arms ſtretcht out, to avoid dangerous objects, run with his Noſe againſt a Poſt; <hi>Cuts ſplutter and nails,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>is her Noſe longer than her Arms?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="285" type="jest">
               <pb n="114" facs="tcp:51789:60"/>
               <head>285.</head>
               <p>A poor Cripple being asked by a Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tleman, why he married a blind woman? <hi>Becauſe,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>we ſhall the better agree, when neither can hit the other in the teeth with their infirmities.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="286" type="jest">
               <head>286.</head>
               <p>King <hi>James</hi> being often troubled with the frequent Petitions of the Scotch Lords, when he was merrily diſpoſed one day, he ſaid to one <hi>Thomas German,</hi> a notable witty perſon, <hi>Suppoſe your ſelf King, and I as you were, how would you behave your ſelf towards theſe Petitioners?</hi> And there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon made <hi>German</hi> ſit down, and he himſelf ſtood at his Elbow, as <hi>German</hi> u<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed to do to him. Then came one Scotch Lord, then another, and another, and all petitioned for ſomething; and <hi>German</hi> ſitting in the Chair of State, ſaid to them, <hi>I am more troubled with theſe Scotch Lords, than all the Kingdom beſides; what can you expect or deſire from me, when here is poor</hi> Tom German, pointing to King <hi>James</hi> at his Elbow, <hi>that hath been faithful to me and ſerved me all along, and I never gave him any thing yet.</hi> This ſo work'd upon the King, that he conſidered all the good ſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vices he had done him, and rewarded him nobly.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="287" type="jest">
               <pb n="115" facs="tcp:51789:60"/>
               <head>287.</head>
               <p>A Reverend Man ſeeing a very chole<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rick couple, married, and living lovingly, asked how they did to live ſo peaceably and comfortably together? To whom the man anſwered, <hi>When my Wives ſit comes upon her, I yield to her; and when my fit is upon me, ſhe yields to me; and ſo we ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver ſtrive together, but aſunder.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="288" type="jest">
               <head>288.</head>
               <p>One told his friend he was mad for ſomething he had done with leſs conſide<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration and judgement than he ought to have done; and that he ought to be ſent to <hi>Bedlam,</hi> to be cured of his Phrenſie, and continued at that rate ſo long, till the other wittily anſwered, <hi>That he wondred much why as in all Commonwealths there was provided a Bedlam for mad men, there never was any place allotted for fools.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="289" type="jest">
               <head>289.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman in <hi>Paris</hi> talking with a Prieſt concerning Religion, asked him why they uſed to kiſs the Croſs more than any other piece of wood? and what was in that more than any Tree elſe, that they did not as well kiſs them? <hi>Why,</hi> ſaid the Prieſt, <hi>is not your Wife made all of the <pb n="116" facs="tcp:51789:61"/>
ſame fleſh and blood, and what's the rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon you do not kiſs her back ſide as well as her face?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="290" type="jest">
               <head>290.</head>
               <p>One having eaten Eggs for Dinner in Lent time, went afterwards to the Ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vern to make up his Dinner with a Glaſs of Wine, but ſtaid ſo long, Pint after Pint, that when he came out into the air, the fumes of the Wine began to load his head, and inſtead of going home ſtrait, he made many reelings croſs the ſtreet; in ſo much that a friend of his ſee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing him, began to chide him for his de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bauchery in the time of Abſtinence; won<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dering he ſaid, that then when there was a time allotted by the Church for the Mortification of the Fleſh, he would make himſelf a reproach and a by-word to all honeſt men. <hi>Alas,</hi> ſays he, <hi>now I ſee how falſe thoſe things are that we com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monly take for truth How often have I heard that an Egge and a Glaſs of Wine would ſuſtain a man four and twenty hours; and it is not two ſince I eat an Egg and drank a Glaſs of Wine, and now you ſee, I cannot ſtand.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="291" type="jest">
               <pb n="117" facs="tcp:51789:61"/>
               <head>291.</head>
               <p>An indifferent Poet ſhewing a Copy of Verſes to a Crooked Gentleman, to have his judgement concerning them; after long peruſal, though he were no great Poet himſelf, nor had any great judge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment in ſuch things; nevertheleſs he told the Poet that he diſliked ſuch and ſuch things, and indeed that he thought they were not well made. <hi>Why then,</hi> ſaid the Poet, taking it in great dudgeon that he ſhould ſlight his Verſes, <hi>all that I can ſay, if they are not well made, is that you will be taken for the Author: for they are made more like you than me.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="292" type="jest">
               <head>292.</head>
               <p>A Countrey Curate having inveyed bitterly againſt the Vices of his Pariſhio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners in his Sermon, one good woman that was there went to ſee his Mother, and ſaid, <hi>That her Son had threatned them all with hell and damnation if they did not a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mend their ways. Oh,</hi> ſaid his Mother, <hi>you are mad if you believe him; for when he was young, he was alwayes a great lyar and I never whipt him, but for ſpeaking un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>truth.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="293" type="jest">
               <pb n="118" facs="tcp:51789:62"/>
               <head>293.</head>
               <p>A Countrey woman ſent her Daughter to a Lady with a preſent of ripe Medlars the clowniſh wench being come to the Lady, told her that her Mother had ſent her Ladyſhip ſome ripe Medlars that were as ſoft as bran; but if ſhe did not eat them quickly, they would not be worth one fart. This language and brutiſh be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>haviour, ſo angred the Gentlewoman, that ſhe reſolved to complain to her Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther of the incivility of her Daughter; and not long after meeting her in the Street, <hi>I thank you very much,</hi> ſaid ſhe, <hi>for your preſent, but the bearer was ſo un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mannerly as to ſay ſuch and ſuch obſcene words. Ah,</hi> replied ſhe, <hi>let me do what I will I cannot mend her; and notwithſtand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing all the civility that ever I taught her, ſhe hath no more manners than mine Arſe.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="294" type="jest">
               <head>294.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman being paſſionately ena<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moured with a fair young woman that was already married, was nevertheleſs ſo far driven by his paſſion, as to ſhew his love on all occaſions to her; which im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portunity when ſhe would endure no longer, and that ſtill he preſſed her more
<pb n="119" facs="tcp:51789:62"/>
and more; telling her he had ſomething to acquaint her with privately. She replied chaſtely and as a wiſe woman, ſhould do, <hi>Sir, when I was under my Parents care, I never did any thing but what they knew and councelled me, and ſince at this time, I am in ſubjection to my Husband, I can do or conſent to nothing but what he knows; there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore if your demands be juſt and honeſt, ask him, and he will ſatisfie you.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="295" type="jest">
               <head>295.</head>
               <p>A poor man having one onely Son, had a mind to bind him out to a Butcher, but being willing to get him a Maſter where he might beſt learn his Trade, he asked his friend to whom he ſhould bind him? <hi>Oh,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>there is a Phyſician in our Vil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lage, bind him to him; for he kills more than all beſide in the Town.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="296" type="jest">
               <head>296.</head>
               <p>A great Scholar, or a meer one, as we ſay, that took care neither for Wife, Children, nor any thing but his Book, was tranſlating a Greek Book into Latine, and at the ſame time one came and told him his Wife was very ſick; <hi>Well I have but three or four ſentences to do,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>and I will come.</hi> Preſently came another and ſaid ſhe was dying; <hi>Well I have but
<pb n="120" facs="tcp:51789:63"/>
three lines,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>to do, and I come.</hi> Not long after came a third, that ſaid ſhe was dead; <hi>Alas, I am ſorry,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>ſhe was a good woman.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="297" type="jest">
               <head>297.</head>
               <p>The King of <hi>France</hi> coming into one of his great Cities, the Mayor came to make a Speech, and began thus, <hi>When the King of Peace rode to Jeruſalem;</hi> but being daſh't out of countenace, he ſaid again, <hi>When the King of Peace rode to Jeruſalem,</hi> and ſo the third time; but could not proceed; then the King turn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to his Courtiers, ſaid, <hi>We may eaſily imagine this man is an Aſs by the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſequent.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="298" type="jest">
               <head>298.</head>
               <p>A ſimple Gentleman falling ſick, ſent to his Phyſician, and deſired him to bring him ſomething that would eaſe his Head-ach, ſo the Phyſician ſent him a Clyſter to purge his Stomach and allay the fumes, whoſe multitude had cauſed that diſtemper; but he being ignorant how it was to be taken, bound it to his head, that it all ran about his ſhoulders: not long af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter the Phyſician, who was now at lea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure; coming to ſee the operations of his Phyſick, wondred to ſee him in that caſe;
<pb n="121" facs="tcp:51789:63"/>
and told him at laſt he ſhould have app<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>y'd it to the other end. So after the Phyſici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>an was gone, <hi>Did you ever ſee,</hi> ſaid he to his friends, <hi>ſuch a ſimple fellow, that ſhould cure my head-ach, and gives me a potion to be apply'd to my back-ſide.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="299" type="jest">
               <head>299.</head>
               <p>One beat his Wife for being very lazy; <hi>Good husdand,</hi> ſaid ſhe, <hi>why do you beat me, I have done nothing. Therefore,</hi> anſwered he, <hi>I beat thee.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="300" type="jest">
               <head>300.</head>
               <p>King <hi>James,</hi> of happy memory, conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dering one day the vanity of his Courti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers in applauding ſtill all his actions, ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry ſeriouſly about noon looked up to hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven out of a window; and demanded of thoſe that were about him, <hi>Whether they ſaw not a ſtar near ſuch a cloud? for,</hi> he ſaid, <hi>he was confident he did.</hi> Whereupon every one looking up, began to deliver their opinions thus, one ſaid, he ſaw it, and that 'twas a little bright ſtar; ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, that it twinkled very much, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry one with a ſeveral addition, conclu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded poſitively as he ſaid: whereupon he ſaid, <hi>How unfortunate a man am I, to have ſo many fools to my Councellors; no wiſer men, than right and wrong to ſay as I ſay.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="301" type="jest">
               <pb n="122" facs="tcp:51789:64"/>
               <head>301.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman, in whoſe face much drinking had raiſed many Pimples came in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to a Barbers Shop, and asked the Barber to ſhave him; but on this condition, That if he ſhaved him and cut any of his Pim<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ples, he would kill him; if not, he would give him a piece of Gold. The Barber li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ked not thoſe terms and plainly denied it; but his man undertook it, and though with great difficulty, yet with as much care he ſhaved him, and never cut him, and h<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>d the piece of Gold. Then ſaid the Gentleman, <hi>Now Sirrah, what would you have done, if you had cut me? Why Sir,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>I ſhould have ſeen the blood firſt, and then I would have cut your threat and pleaded it was by accident.</hi> Which words ſo wrought upon the Gentleman, that e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver after he ſhaved himſelf.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="302" type="jest">
               <head>302.</head>
               <p>The King going to ſee his new Palace, as it was building, a Courtier not over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe, happened to be in his Retinue; and when they had been there a little while, the Maſter Workman came and gave them an account of ſuch and ſuch Lodgings; and every one judged ſomething to be ſo and ſo: at laſt comes m<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> ſimple Courtier,
<pb n="123" facs="tcp:51789:64"/>
thinking to ſay ſomething as well as the reſt; and asks what that black Marble was for? The Maſter Workman replied it was for the Houſe of Office. <hi>Ah, let us go away,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>I knew it was ſo; for I ſmelt it above an hour ago.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="203" type="jest">
               <head>203.</head>
               <p>A witty Fellow in <hi>London,</hi> took one day many Rams-Horns in his Basket, and went up and down the City crying, <hi>New fruit, New fruit,</hi> in the Winter. This made many people, and amongſt the reſt, a Lawyer, to call him to him; who ſee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing his Ware, laught at him, ſaying, <hi>You fool, who do you think will buy your horns? Oh Sir,</hi> replied he, <hi>though you are provi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded, yet I may meet with ſome that are not.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="304" type="jest">
               <head>304.</head>
               <p>A ſimple Peaſant lying on night upon the ground, and finding it very uneaſie, when he awaked in the morning, ſaw a feather under his head. <hi>Oh,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>doth one feather cauſe me ſo much diſeaſe, how are they troubled that lie on whole feather beds?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="305" type="jest">
               <head>305.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Virgil</hi> the famous Poet, was much in favour, through his great learning and
<pb n="124" facs="tcp:51789:65"/>
judgment, with <hi>Auguſtus;</hi> in ſo much that he had his bread from him. <hi>Auguſtus,</hi> one day, knowing his deep diſcretion, asked him privately if he could gueſs who was his Father? To which he replied, <hi>Truly Sir, I do verily believe he was a Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ker.</hi> And when that <hi>Ceſar</hi> asked the rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon? <hi>Becauſe,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>you always reward me with bread.</hi> With which anſwer, <hi>Auguſtus</hi> being well pleaſed, rewarded him afterwards with money.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="306" type="jest">
               <head>306.</head>
               <p>A poor Scholar in <hi>France</hi> being very hungry, came into a Shop where <hi>Petits Pates</hi> were ſold, and aked what he ſhould give the Man to let him eat his Bel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly full? He told him he ſhould give him Twenty pence. The Scholar told him he would give Fifteen; and the Man took him at his word. So the Scholar ſate down, and eat the firſt Oven full; which contained four dozen. The Man ſeeing that, asked if he would not drink a Glaſs of Wine? <hi>Oh no, not yet,</hi> replied he, <hi>I do not uſe to drink, till the third Oven full.</hi> So the poor fellow was glad to let him go with what he had eaten, without paying a farthing; for fear he ſhould have undone him.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="307" type="jest">
               <pb n="125" facs="tcp:51789:65"/>
               <head>307.</head>
               <p>Pope <hi>Alexander</hi> being accuſtomed highly to commend the Inſtitution of the Single Life of Prieſts, and to blame their uſing of Concubines, was wont to ſay, <hi>God hath forbidden us to get Children, and the Devil hath given us Nephews.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="308" type="jest">
               <head>308.</head>
               <p>Pope <hi>Boniface</hi> being told by one of his Court, that there was a Pilgrim of the Countrey of <hi>Bavaria,</hi> come to <hi>Rome,</hi> of purpoſe to viſit the Religious Places of the City; who did altogether reſemble him both in perſon and in countenance. <hi>Boni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>face</hi> having cauſed him to be ſent for to his preſence, demanded of him, <hi>If his Mother had ever been at</hi> Rome? The Pil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>grim perceiving himſelf touch'd with ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſition of Baſtardy, anſwered, <hi>Holy Father, My Mother was never in this Countrey, but my Father hath been here many times.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="309" type="jest">
               <head>309.</head>
               <p>Some good Companions being very merry together, fell into a Diſcourſe con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning Beards; and ſome pretended to conjecture others qualities and conditions by their Beards: at laſt, in continuance of the diſcourſe, one who had a red Beard
<pb n="124" facs="tcp:51789:66"/>
                  <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                     <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb n="125" facs="tcp:51789:66"/>
                  <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                     <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb n="126" facs="tcp:51789:67"/>
and hair much of the ſame colour, was ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry deſirous to know what they thought ofhim? <hi>Why I ſhould gueſs,</hi> ſaid another, <hi>by your Cow-colour'd beard, that you are a Calf.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="310" type="jest">
               <head>310.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman going one night to the Houſe of Office, bid his Footman bring the candle and light him; which being done, when the Gentleman had done what he came to do, he pulled out a Letter out of his pocket, and was going to tear it: Whereupon the Footman deſired to have it, and he would give him ſome other paper: <hi>Why, what would you do with it?</hi> ſaid his Maſter. <hi>Oh, Sir,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>my Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther in the Countrey would fain have me ſend her ſome Letters, and I cannot write; ſo I would ſend her that.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="311" type="jest">
               <head>311.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman being at a Feaſt amongſt much company, where every one had his Lacquey waiting on him, called his Foot-boy to change his Trencher, on which there was a whole Chick; the Youth ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king it away, had no ſooner ſet it down, but he perceived the other Lacqueys to caſt an eye at it, for they took away no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing but bones; ſo fearing leſt they
<pb n="127" facs="tcp:51789:67"/>
ſhould ſteal it away he brings it on a Tren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cher to his Maſter, deſiring <hi>he would let it ſtand by him; for there were ſo many greedy guts, that he feared they would ſteal it.</hi> His Maſter ſeeing his ſimplicity, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peated the ſtory to the company, which cauſed very great mirth.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="312" type="jest">
               <head>312.</head>
               <p>A Felon being to be hang'd in a Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trey-Town, word was ſent to the Carpen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter to make a Gibbet; but he neglected to do it, and the day of execution was de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferred, which cauſed the Judge to be very angry who ſent for the Carpenter, asking, <hi>why he had not done it. Why, Sir,</hi> replied he, <hi>I have done two or three already, and ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver was paid for them; but had I known it had been for your Worſhip. I would have left all other buſineſs to have done it.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="313" type="jest">
               <head>313.</head>
               <p>Some Hogards being together, and talking of the King, one ſaid, <hi>If he were King, he would eat fat every day;</hi> the other, <hi>that he would have now ſhoes every month;</hi> the third, <hi>that he would be carried upon a Cart-load of Hay, with his belly up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward, all day long;</hi> the fourth being de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded what he would do; <hi>Oh,</hi> ſays he, <hi>you have wiſh'd for all the beſt things al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ready,
<pb n="128" facs="tcp:51789:68"/>
and left me nothing worth deſiring.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="314" type="jest">
               <head>314.</head>
               <p>A Countrey Farmer's Wife having lent her Man a Mare to ride to the Wood, the Mare th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ew him, and ran away to the Wood her ſelf, where the Wolf's eat her: His Miſtris brought him before the Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice to make him pay for the Mare. So he goes to a Lawyer to know what he ſhould do; the Lawyer not being at home, his Wife deſired the Man to ſtay. But at laſt, when he was tired with expecting him, he told her he cou'd ſtay no longer; but, if ſhe pleaſed, he would tell her his buſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs. Sir, ſaid ſhe, I do not much know theſe kind of matters; but if you pleaſe to tell it, I am willing to hear it. Then be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ginning to tell his ſtory, he ſo intangled himſelf, that ſhe could not underſtand him, and deſired him to ſpeak more plain. <hi>Why then, Madam,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>ſuppoſe you were a Mare, I ſaddle, I bridle, I girt you, I get up upon you; you kick, you fart, you play the devil, throw me off, and run away to the Wood, and the Wolf eat you; muſt I pay for you. No ſurely,</hi> replied ſhe<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> 
                  <hi>Why then, Madam,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>my caſe is good.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="315" type="jest">
               <pb n="129" facs="tcp:51789:68"/>
               <head>315.</head>
               <p>A woman going to Maſs to preſent her Tapers, fixed one to Saint <hi>Michael,</hi> and another to the Devil that was at his feet. The Clerk ſeeing that, came and told her ſhe had done amiſs, in offering that Candle to the Devil, <hi>No matter,</hi> ſaid ſhe, <hi>'tis good to have friends every where, for we know not where we ſhall go.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="316" type="jest">
               <head>316.</head>
               <p>One accuſing another before a Judge, ſaid, <hi>He was a debauch'd perſon, a rogue, and a thief. Do you here,</hi> ſaid the Judge, <hi>how he ſays you are a debauch'd perſon, a rogue, and a thief? How ſo,</hi> repli'd he, <hi>pray, Sir, did not he ſpeak to you?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="317" type="jest">
               <head>317.</head>
               <p>A drunken young Heir, that ſold all his Lands to maintain his luſt, when by much eating and drinking he fell into a diſtem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per, ſent for the Phyſician to have his ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice, who perceiving his diſeaſe to ariſe from abundance of ill humours, cauſed him to be let bloud; and about an hour after the Chyrurgeon had been here, he came to ſee the bloud, to judge by it; and looking upon it, <hi>Sir,</hi> ſaid <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>e, <hi>your bloud is very green. Alas,</hi> reply'd the Youth, <hi>how can it be otherwiſe? I have
<pb n="130" facs="tcp:51789:69"/>
eaten all my Meadows and Corn-fields.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="318" type="jest">
               <head>318.</head>
               <p>'Tis uſual in <hi>Spain</hi> to have Croſſes at the end of, or near every Town; ſo a <hi>Spaniard</hi> travelling, when night came on, eſpied a Croſs, but when he came up to it, there was no Town near it; and having travelled two Leagues farther with much pain and trouble, at laſt he ſaw a Gibbet, and preſently came to a Town: <hi>Well,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>henceforward I ſhall ſooner believe in a Gibbet, then the Croſs.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="319" type="jest">
               <head>319.</head>
               <p>A Fiſherman having brought to ſhoar great ſtore of Soles, gave notice by the Crier to the Town, that ſuch Fiſh were come in, and were to be ſold at ſuch a place: Some bought of them, others ſaid they ſtank, ſome ſaid this, and ſome that. A Gentleman that had bought ſome, gave order to his Maid to dreſs them; which, as ſhe was doing, the Cat eat one; which ſo incenſed the Maid, that ſhe took a great ſtick and knock'd her in the head. Her Maſter coming in, ask'd her, why ſhe had done it? and when he knew and perceived there was no remedy, he took the Cat and threw it out into the ſtreet among the people, ſaying, <hi>See, there's a Cat that's
<pb n="131" facs="tcp:51789:69"/>
dead with eating a Sole.</hi> The people a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>larm'd with this, ſuppoſing the Cat to be poiſon'd, ran to the Fiſherman, and threw all his Fiſh about the ſtreet, and carri<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>d him before the Judge, for intending to poiſon the Town. The poor man, igno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant of the cauſe of this dyſaſter, ſtill pleaded his Fiſh were new and ſound. The Judge, to know the certainty of the matter, ſent for the Gentleman, who re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>l<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ted the ſtory with much mirth. But the poor Fiſherman went away ſorrowing for his loſs.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="320" type="jest">
               <head>320.</head>
               <p>A <hi>Spaniard</hi> and a <hi>Gaſcoign</hi> coming both in together to an Inn, in <hi>France,</hi> found nothing ready but a piece of Mutton and a Partridge; ſo one would have the Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tridge, and another would have it, and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gan to quarrel. The Hoſteſs deſired they would be pleaſed to eat it together but the Bragadocio <hi>Spaniard,</hi> whoſe head was building Caſtles in the Air, ſaid, <hi>It ſhould be reſerved till the morning, and he that dream'd the beſt dream, ſhould eat it for his breakfaſt.</hi> So eating the Mutton for their ſupper, they went to bed. The <hi>Spa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niard</hi> could not ſleep one wink, for think<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing what he ſhould dream. The <hi>Gaſcoign</hi>
                  <pb n="132" facs="tcp:51789:70"/>
having obſerved where the Partridge was ſet, aroſe in the night, and eat it. The next morning when both were up, the <hi>Spaniard</hi> fearing the other might ſay his dream, which he thought was the beſt, ſaid very haſtily, that he dream'd the rareſt dream in the world, <hi>That he ſaw the Heavens open, and that a Quire of Angels carri'd him up with Muſick to Heaven.</hi> Then ſaid the <hi>Gaſcoign, I dream'd, that I ſaw you carri'd up to Heaven; and thinking you would never come down again, I roſe and eat the Partridge; for I knew you would have no need of meat in Heaven.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="321" type="jest">
               <head>321.</head>
               <p>Two <hi>Gaſcoigns</hi> came to <hi>Paris,</hi> to live their by the ſleight of their hand, knavery, ſtealth, and ſuch like endow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, as their poor Countrey had fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſh'd them with; but being both appre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hended, one, who had been branded be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore, was hang'd on a Gibbet, the other was whipt at the foot of it. The latter having eſcap'd ſo well, returned back to his own Countrey; and after he was wel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>com'd home by his friends, many enquir'd what was become of his Friend and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>panion. <hi>Oh,</hi> ſays he, <hi>he hath made true the ſaying, That no body is a Prophet in his
<pb n="133" facs="tcp:51789:70"/>
own Countrey. How ſo?</hi> ſaid they. <hi>Becauſe,</hi> repli'd he, <hi>he is marri'd.</hi> And when they asked, <hi>To whom?</hi> He anſwered, <hi>To one of a high quality, and that he danced at his Wedding.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="322" type="jest">
               <head>322.</head>
               <p>A <hi>Welchman</hi> being condemn'd to be hang'd, when he was brought to the place of execution, and was ready to be turn'd off, the Hangman ask'd him if he had ought to ſay. <hi>Yes,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>I would wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lingly ſpeak to ſome of my Countrey, if any be here.</hi> Then the Hangman call<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>d out to know if any ſuch were there, he ſhould hold up his hand. It hapned one was there, to whom the Hangman ſaid. <hi>That poor man would ſpeak with him.</hi> So when he drew near, he asked, <hi>if he knew ſuch perſons in Wales.</hi> The other repli'd, <hi>He did. Then,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>you know my father and mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, who, I know, will be much griev'd at my misfortune: but pray, to comfort them, tell them, I die a good Chriſtian, and am cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tainly informed that I ſhall go to heaven; and I hope they will follow me thither the ſame way.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="323" type="jest">
               <head>323.</head>
               <p>A Gentleman coming into <hi>London</hi> out of the Countrey, as he came by <hi>New
<pb n="134" facs="tcp:51789:71"/>
Chappel,</hi> his Horſe threw him; which a young Gentlewoman ſeeing, fell a laugh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing. The Gentleman being angry that ſhe je<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>red him, ſaid, <hi>Pray wonder not at this, Madam, my Horſe always ſtumbles when he ſees a Whore.</hi> To which ſhe anſwer<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>d merrily, <hi>Have a care then, Sir, for if you ride into the City, you will break your neck.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="324" type="jest">
               <head>324.</head>
               <p>Three drunkards having been late a drinking, and knowing what a peal their Wives would ring them when they came home, lai'd a wager among themſelves of ten pounds a man, that they would all obey what their Wives firſt commanded them and would do it. So coming to the firſt man's houſe, his Wife had prepared a good ſtaff for him, and as ſoon as he came home, ſell upon him; he ſtepping back, trode upon an earthen diſh, and broke it. <hi>Ay you Rogue,</hi> ſaid his Wife, <hi>do, go, break all.</hi> So he up with his ſtaff, and broke the windows, and all the pots, till at laſt ſhe beat him out of doors. Then they went to the Second's houſe, his Wife was of the ſame temper, and fell upon him, that ſtriving for haſte to get away, he let a Fart: <hi>Ay, go ſhit, you drunken Rogue,</hi>
                  <pb n="135" facs="tcp:51789:71"/>
ſaid his Wife, <hi>go.</hi> So he down with his breeches and Shit in the room. Then they went to the third<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>s houſe, where the Good-man being pretty well in drink, he ſtumbled over the threſhold: <hi>Ay, you drunken Rogue,</hi> ſaid his Wife, <hi>go, break your neck, do. A pox on you for a Whore,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>you have made me loſe my wager.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="325" type="jest">
               <head>325.</head>
               <p>A certain Papiſt, that never carri'd Beads about him, was ask'd the reaſon by his friend, who accuſed him of his being Irreligious. <hi>Oh,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>I have a Wi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>e, who is ſo lean, that in ſtead of Beads, I can count the bones in her back, and ſay my proyers ſo often Yes, but,</hi> ſaid the other, <hi>when you have gone as low as you can, do you then kiſs.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="326" type="jest">
               <head>326.</head>
               <p>A Curate in the Countrey had made the poor people believe he was a Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jurer, and a great Diviner; a Lord there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore ſent one day for him, and queſtion'd if he could Divine; ſo he plainly con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſs'd he could not, but that the vulgar people had reported it onely of him. <hi>Nay,</hi> repli'd the Lord, <hi>that will not ſerve, either you muſt tell me four things that I ſhall ask you, or reſolve to be diſpoſſeſſed of all your
<pb n="136" facs="tcp:51789:72"/>
Preferment as a Cheat, a Deluder, and Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſtor.</hi> Thus when there was no hope of eſcape, he deſired him to propoſe his queſtions, and to give him two days to conſider on them. The Lord gave him that time, and ſaid, <hi>Firſt, you muſt tell me where the middle of the world is. Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>condly, what I am worth. Then what I think, Laſtly, what I believe.</hi> The Curate went away much perplexed what to anſwer; but in his way a ſubtil Joyner of his ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quaintance met him, and by much per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwaſions got out of him the cauſe of his melancholly. <hi>Well,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>troub<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>e not your ſelf; lend me your robes, and I will clear you of this matter.</hi> So the day being come, the Joyner inveſts himſe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>f with the Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rates Gown, and goes away betimes in the morning to the Lord, that was not yet ſtirring; nevertheleſs the Lord wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to hear his anſwers, got up: <hi>Well,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>what do you think of the queſtions? where is the middle of the world? Why,</hi> reply'd he, <hi>if you pleaſe to go out with me into the fields, I ſhall ſhew you, for it is hard by. Is it poſſible?</hi> ſays the Lord. So out they both went, and the Joyner having drawn a Circle to colour the matter, and ſome ſtrange figures, at laſt ſtuck down his ſtick,
<pb n="137" facs="tcp:51789:72"/>
and ſaid, <hi>Juſt there is the middle. But how ſhall I know?</hi> reply'd the Lord. <hi>Why if you pleaſe to meaſure it,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>and it wants but one hands-breadth, I will forfeit my life. Well,</hi> ſaid the Lord, <hi>what am I worth, all my debts paid? Why,</hi> anſwer'd he, <hi>our Saviour was ſold but for thirty pence, and if I ſay you are worth but nine and twenty, I think I do you no great wrong.</hi> Then the Lord ask'd him, <hi>what he thought. You think,</hi> reply'd he, <hi>more, I am ſure, on your profit then on mine.</hi> Laſtly, he ask'd, <hi>what he believ'd. Why you believe,</hi> ſaid the Joyner, <hi>that I am the Curate, but I am onely a poor Joyner.</hi> Which cauſed the Lord to diſmiſs him with a reward of his inge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nuity, laughing heartily at his witty anſwers.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="327" type="jest">
               <head>327.</head>
               <p>Three Soldiers talking together, were overheard by a Courtier to ſay thus; one ſaid, <hi>Had he a thouſand pounds he ſhould be happier then the King;</hi> The other ſaid, <hi>Were he a Captain under the King, he ſhould be happier then he;</hi> The laſt, <hi>That had he one nights lodging with the Queen, he ſhould be the happieſt man in the world.</hi> The Courtier related this to his <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ing, and the King for divertiſement ſent for theſe
<pb n="138" facs="tcp:51789:73"/>
three the next day before him, and bid them upon pain of death confeſs, and tell what they ſaid the night before, at ſuch a time. The firſt fearing the King's anger, ſaid <hi>That he had indeed raſhly ſaid, That if he had a thouſand pounds, he ſhould be as happy as the King.</hi> So the King com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded that a thouſand pound ſhould be given him. The ſecond deſired his Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſty's pardon for his bold ſaying, <hi>That had he a Captain's command under him, he ſhould be as happy as he.</hi> Then the King con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferr'd that Office upon him. The third fell down on his knees, begging pardon from the King, foraſmuch as he had ſaid, <hi>That if he lay one night with the Queen, he ſhould be the happieſt man in the world. Well,</hi> ſaid the King, <hi>that is not in my power to grant; but if thou canſt get here conſent, thou haſt mine.</hi> So he brought him before his Queen, and told his petition. But the Queen, to ſhow that our deſires ought to be placed on ſuitable objects, cauſed him to be well whipt.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="328" type="jest">
               <head>328.</head>
               <p>A <hi>Spaniard</hi> and a <hi>Frenchman</hi> contend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing about Religion; <hi>Why</hi> quoth the <hi>Spa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niard, will you contend with us for Religion? there are more Saints that have been Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>noniz'd
<pb n="139" facs="tcp:51789:73"/>
in</hi> Spain, <hi>then there be hairs on my beard. And there are more in</hi> France, ſaid the <hi>Frenchman, then I have hairs on my beard and my head. Then,</hi> ſaid the <hi>Spa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niard, let this decide it, I will pull a hair off your beard for every Saint I name, and you ſhall pull one off mine for every Saint you name.</hi> So the Frenchman began, and pull'd one off the <hi>Spaniard</hi>'s beard, crying, <hi>St. Denis.</hi> Then the <hi>Spaniard</hi> doing the like, ſaid, <hi>St. Ignace.</hi> The <hi>Frenchman</hi> pulling another, ſaid, <hi>St. Martin.</hi> The <hi>Spaniard, St. Xavier.</hi> The <hi>Frenchman, St. Louis.</hi> The <hi>Spaniard, St. Tereſe.</hi> The <hi>Frenchman, St. Clotilde.</hi> The <hi>Spaniard, St. Iſidore.</hi> The <hi>Frenchman, St. Bun.</hi> The <hi>Spaniard</hi> plucking two at once, ſaid, <hi>St. Coſine and St. Damian.</hi> The <hi>Frenchman</hi> reſolving to be revenged, took a whole Muſtache, and pull'd it off, ſaying, <hi>The eleven thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand Virgins.</hi> Upon this the diſpute ended, the <hi>Spaniard</hi> not being able to endure, or parallel ſo great a number.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="329" type="jest">
               <head>329.</head>
               <p>A Sergeant coming to ſeize upon the goods of a poor woman for her Husbands debt, would be put off by no complaints of the poor woman, and was ſo unrea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſonable, as to take the very kettle off the
<pb n="140" facs="tcp:51789:74"/>
fire, that ſtood upon a Trevet. The woman ſeeing that, took up the Trevet with the Tongs, and clapt it upon his head, which burn'd him deeply, and mark'd him for a Rogue.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="330" type="jest">
               <head>330.</head>
               <p>A <hi>Cordelier</hi> and a <hi>Jacobin</hi> mee<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ing at the ſame Inn, the next morning the <hi>Ja<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cobin</hi> paid his reckoning; but the <hi>Cordelier</hi> ſuppoſing to have come off every where with <hi>Retribuet Dominus,</hi> was forced by the Maſter of the houſe, who was a Prote<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtant, to pay for what he had had. Then he deſired the <hi>Jacobin</hi> to lend him ſo much. But he ſaid, he had no more then would juſt bear his charges; ſo that the <hi>Cordelier</hi> was forced to pawn his Books. The next day they went out together, both being to go the ſame way; and it ſo fell out, that in their p<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ſſage they came to a pl<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ſh of water; the poor <hi>Cordelier</hi> put off his Sandals, and holding up his Gown, began to go through. The <hi>Jaco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bin</hi> that was rich, and well dreſs'd, could not tell what to do. At laſt the <hi>Cordelier</hi> asked what he would give him to carry him over? The other reply'd, That he would redeem his Books, and pay for him at the next Inn. So the <hi>Cordelier</hi> took
<pb n="141" facs="tcp:51789:74"/>
him on his back, and as he came into the middle. But have you money to defray our charges? ſaid he. Yes, that I have, anſwered the <hi>Jacobin;</hi> and to ſhow it was true, clapt one hand in his pocket to make it chink. The <hi>Cordelier</hi> having this opportunity and advantage, and reſolving to be revenged on him, let him fall into the middle, and went away laughing on the other ſide, ſaying, <hi>You have made me tranſgreſs my Orders, for I am never to carry money about me.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="331" type="jest">
               <head>331.</head>
               <p>A witty Gentleman, and a lover of mirth, being invited by his friend to din<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner, and a diſh of Partridges being ſet before him, he went to take one; but the claws of it were ſo intangled with the claws of another, that he could not eaſily get them aſſunder: <hi>Nay,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>if you fight all day, and are reſolved to do ſo, I ſhall never part you;</hi> and ſo took them both to his plate.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="332" type="jest">
               <head>332.</head>
               <p>A young Boy having a Godfather that was a Phyſician, would by a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>l means be of that profeſſion, notwithſtanding he ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver learned Latin, or any other Lan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guage then his own. His Godfather
<pb n="142" facs="tcp:51789:75"/>
therefore to inſtruct him ſpeedily, and to make a ſhort cut of the buſineſs, told him, <hi>That a good way to judge the cauſe of a perſons ſickneſs, was, to look up and down the chamber, what fragments of victuals he could ſpie, and then ask if the ſick perſon had not eaten ſuch and ſuch a thing; whereby people ſhould much admire his great judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment.</hi> The Youth inſtructed with ſuch and the like principles, goes out a hopeful Quack, and the firſt ſick gowty perſon he came to, he pry'd up and down the cham<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber, and at laſt ſaw a Saddle; ſo when he came to the party, and found him much ſwell'd; <hi>Alas, Sir,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>'tis no marvel you are ſo ſwell'd, you have eaten a great deal too much Horſe-fleſh.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="333" type="jest">
               <head>333.</head>
               <p>One having call'd a Maid, Whore, that was ſo indeed, nevertheleſs, becauſe he could not prove her ſo, ſhe brought him before the Juſtice; nevertheleſs he abſolved himſelf with a witty equivoca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> for the Juſtice that knew him very well, ſaid, <hi>Sir, this Maid accuſes you for calling her Whore I call'd her Whore,</hi> re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ply'd he, <hi>'tis true. But now I ſay ſhe's an honeſt Maid, I lied.</hi> So the Juſtice laughing at his ſubtilty, diſmiſs'd him.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="334" type="jest">
               <pb n="143" facs="tcp:51789:75"/>
               <head>334.</head>
               <p>A Sergeant coming to a Lord, and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>having himſelf very rudely, ſaid, when the others asked how he dared be ſo bold, <hi>That he cared for no body. Why,</hi> reply'd they, <hi>doſt thou not know that he is ab<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>e to give thee a thouſand ſtripes. That's nothing,</hi> ſaid he; <hi>for if he ſcratches, I can bite.</hi> The Lord afterwards calling him to him, de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded the cauſe that made him threaten him, ſince he had given him no reaſon to be angry, and ſaid, <hi>That to take away all fear of his ſcratching him, he would have his nails cut;</hi> and then commanded his man to cut them preſently. <hi>Now,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>'tis reaſon you ſhould be hindred likewiſe of biting me;</hi> and therefore commanded his men to pull out all his teeth.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="335" type="jest">
               <head>335.</head>
               <p>A Countrey Peaſant having been at Confeſſion with his Curate, and that had told him, that he had eaten Eggs that Lent, and was reproved, for as much as Eggs made Chickens; Chickens, Cocks; and Cocks, Capons: not long after, when the Curate ſent to him for a dozen Eggs to ſet under a Hen, he ſent to him a dozen boiled hard. The Curate ignorant of that, ſet them under
<pb n="144" facs="tcp:51789:76"/>
his Hen, but at three weeks end, when he ſaw no Chickens, he broke one Egg, and found it hard, then he broke another, and ſo all, one by one, finding them to be boyled. This made him go in great haſte to the Peaſant, to know the reaſon why he had thus impoſed upon him. But the Peaſant told him, he did not know what he meant. <hi>Why you fool,</hi> quoth the Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rate, <hi>did you ever think that Chickens could be hatch'd out of hard Eggs? Why ſo you told me, Sir,</hi> quoth he, <hi>laſt Lent; for when I confeſſed to you that I had eaten Eggs, you chid me, ſaying, Eggs made Chickens, Chickens grew to be Cocks, and Cocks were made Capons: now if boyled Eggs which I eat, would ever have been Cocks and Capons, how did I know but the boyl'd Eggs under your Hen would come to be ſo too?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="339" type="jest">
               <head>339.</head>
               <p>A certain old man, a poor Labourer of the Countrey, ſeeing the Archbiſhop of <hi>Cologn</hi> to ride through the fields, armed, and accompanied with armed Forces, fell out in a loud laughing: Whereupon be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing demanded why he laughed, he an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwerd, <hi>Becauſe he wondred that St. Peter, Chriſt's Vicar in the Church, being ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeding</hi>
                  <pb n="145" facs="tcp:51789:76"/>
poor, had left his Succeſſor ſo rich and wealthy; and that his Train ſhould be more furniſhed with Men at Arms than with Churchmen. The Arch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>biſhop deſired that the fellow ſhould have better knowledge of him in his Place and Dignity; and told him that he was not onely an Archbiſhop but a Duke alſo; and that as a Duke he rode ſo accompani<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed with a Train of Men at Arms: but when he was in his Church, then he was attended on as an Archbiſhop. <hi>Sir,</hi> ſaid the Labourer, <hi>I pray tell me, when my Lord Duke ſhall be with the Devil, what will become of the Archbiſhop?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="337" type="jest">
               <head>337.</head>
               <p>The Emperour <hi>Sigiſmond</hi> and one of his Pages paſſing over a certain River at a Foard on Horsback, when they were in the midſt of the River, the Empero<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>s Horſe ſtood ſtill and began to ſtale; which the Page ſeeing, he ſaid to the Emperour, <hi>Moſt Sacred Prince, your Horſe is ill taught, and reſembleth you ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry much.</hi> The Emperour anſwered not, but rode on to his Lodging, where being come, and in pulling off his Boots, he demanded of his Page why he had likened
<pb n="146" facs="tcp:51789:77"/>
his Horſe to him? <hi>Becauſe,</hi> quoth the Page, <hi>the River had no need of any water, yet your Horſe in piſſing there, did adde water to water; and ſo do you, for you give wealth and riches to them which have plen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty; but to ſuch as have none, you given t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> any. And it is long time ſince I have been with you, yet I never taſted of your liberali<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty.</hi> The Emperor the next morning took two little Iron Coffers, yet one was ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>what bigger, which he filled with Lead; the other with Duckets; and bid his Page take one of them, which he would, for his long ſervice. The Page chuſing the biggeſt, <hi>Now open it,</hi> ſaid the Emperour, <hi>and ſee what is within it;</hi> which he did, and found it to be Lead. Then ſaid the Emperour, <hi>Now thou knoweſt thy fortune, the fault was none of mine, that thy choice was no better and that thou wert not made rich; for thou haſt refuſed thy good fortune when it was offered thee.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="338" type="jest">
               <head>338.</head>
               <p>A witty Gentlewoman, after her Huſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bands deceaſe, was perſwaded to live ſtil a Widdow, in imitation, and by the ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ample of the Turtle, which after the death of the male, keeps continual cha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtity.
<pb n="147" facs="tcp:51789:77"/>
To which ſhe made anſwer, <hi>If I muſt follow the conditions of the Birds, why do not you as well tell me of the Dove and the Sparrow.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="339" type="jest">
               <head>339.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Lewis</hi> the Groſs King of <hi>France,</hi> taking part with <hi>Holy</hi> Earl of <hi>Maine,</hi> againſt <hi>Henry</hi> King of <hi>England,</hi> in a Battel fought between them, found himſelf far ſevered from his people. A certain En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gliſh Knight ſeeing him, and being in hope to make himſelf rich, by taking him Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoner, laid hands upon the Reins of the Kings Horſe, with intent to ſtay him, and began to cry aloud, <hi>The King is ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken.</hi> The King being valiant and of a noble courage, at one blow with his Sword overthrew the dead Knight to the ground: and ſeeing him fall, ſaid, <hi>It is not one Knight alone that can give the King the Mate.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="340" type="jest">
               <head>340.</head>
               <p>A certain bold Souldier was very im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portunate with a Gentleman to give him ſomething for the loſſes and damages he had received in the Wars, and ſhewed the wounds he had received in his viſage. The Gentleman ſeeing him ſo raſh and
<pb n="148" facs="tcp:51789:78"/>
audacious, reſolved to fit him for his boaſting and oſtentation, ſaying, <hi>Take heed thou turn not thy face another time, when thou art flying from the enemy.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="341" type="jest">
               <head>341.</head>
               <p>A certain Courtier finding the King in a good humor, as they diſcourſed of Dreams, ſaid with a good grace before all the Company, how the night before he dreamt, <hi>That the King beſtowed upon him a bag of Guineys.</hi> Whereunto the King preſently anſwered, <hi>Why are you ſo fooliſh as to think a Chriſtian man ought to believe Dreams.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="342" type="jest">
               <head>342.</head>
               <p>In the City of <hi>Conſtantinople</hi> a certain Chriſtian deſired to borrow of a Jew the ſum of Five hundred Duckets. The Jew lent them unto him, with condition, that for the uſe of the money, he ſhould at the end of the term give him two oun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces of his fleſh, cut off in ſome one of his members. The day of payment be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing come, the Chriſtian repayed the Five hundred Duckets to the Jew, but refu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed to give him any part of his fleſh. The Jew not willing to loſe his intereſt, convented the Chriſtian before Sultan <hi>So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liman,</hi>
                  <pb n="149" facs="tcp:51789:78"/>
Emperour of the Turks, who ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving heard the wicked demand of the one, and the anſwer of the other, com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded a Razor to be brought and to be given to the Jew, to whom he ſaid, <hi>Becauſe thou ſhalt know that Juſtice is done thee, take there the Razor and cut from the fleſh of the Chriſtian two ounces, which thou demandeſt; but take heed thou cut neither more nor leſs; for if thou doſt, thou ſhalt ſurely die.</hi> The Jew holding that to be a thing impoſſible, durſt not adventure, but acquitted the Chriſtian his Intereſt.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="343" type="jest">
               <head>343.</head>
               <p>The Pope, who will have the diſpoſing of Kingdoms and Dominions and Em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pires, when he conſulted of taking up Arms againſt the Saracens, made <hi>Sancti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>us</hi> Brother to the King of <hi>Spain,</hi> for his valour, hardineſs, and good parts, King of <hi>Egypt;</hi> which was immediately pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>claimed. <hi>Sanctius</hi> not underſtanding Latine, in which Language the Cryer proclaimed him King of <hi>Egypt;</hi> and hearing the loud Acclamations of the Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple, asked what they were for? who ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving told him that the Pope had grant<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed
<pb n="150" facs="tcp:51789:79"/>
and proclaimed him King of <hi>Egypt,</hi> he ſaid unto his Interpreter, <hi>Stand up, and make here preſently a Proclamation be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore all this people, that ſeeing the Pope hath made me King of</hi> Egypt, <hi>I make him Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liph of</hi> Babylon.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="344" type="jest">
               <head>344.</head>
               <p>The Duke of <hi>Millain</hi> being beſieged in a Caſtle by the Florentines; one day as he ſate at Dinner, he could not away, but fell in miſlike with the taſte of the Victuals that were ſet before him; inſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>much that he chid his Cook, and was very angry with him. But the witty Cook willing to juſtifie himſelf from blame, ſaid unto the Duke, <hi>My Lord, your mean is well though dreſſed, but the Florentines have put your mouth out of taſte.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="345" type="jest">
               <head>345.</head>
               <p>The Poet <hi>Dant</hi> demanded of a Citizen of <hi>Florence, What hour it was?</hi> who an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwered him very rudely, <hi>That it was the hour, in which Horſes go to be watered. Dant</hi> ſuddenly replied, <hi>What doeſt thou here then, that thou art not gone?</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="346" type="jest">
               <pb n="151" facs="tcp:51789:79"/>
               <head>346.</head>
               <p>Before the Battel fought at <hi>Serizoles,</hi> the Marquiſs of <hi>Guaſt,</hi> aſſuring himſelf of the Victory, gave his Jeſter a fair gilt Armor and a Spaniſh Jennet, and pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſed to give him Five hundred Duckets, to the intent he ſhould be the firſt that ſhould carry the News to his wife. But it happened that the French beat the Em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perors Army, and the Jeſter was taken and brought before the Lord <hi>Anguien,</hi> who perceiving what he was asked who had furniſhed him in that order? <hi>My Lord,</hi> replied he, <hi>the Marquiſs gave me my Horſe and Arms; and ſhould have gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven me Five hundred Duckets to go and tell my Lady his Wife, the firſt tidings of his Victory: but I believe he will gain the mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney himſelf, and is poſted thither in per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="347" type="jest">
               <head>347.</head>
               <p>A Lords Fool ſeeing the Maids carry down much water into the Cellar to waſh, cry'd, <hi>Fire, Fire,</hi> at which all the Neighbours ran to help; but the Lord not knoiwng how the matter was, ſearched all his Houſe, and when all was found ſafe, he thanked his good Neigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bours
<pb n="152" facs="tcp:51789:80"/>
for their kindneſs, and diſmiſt them. Not long after the Maids began to carry down more water, and the Fool began to cry <hi>Fire, Fire,</hi> again: ſo the Lord came out and ask'd him why he cry'd Fire? <hi>Why,</hi> ſaid he, <hi>I ſee them carry down ſo much water, and I thought there was Fire.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="publishers_advertisement">
            <pb facs="tcp:51789:80"/>
            <head>Books printed for, and ſold by <hi>Samuel Lowndes</hi> at his Shop over againſt <hi>Exeter</hi> Houſe in the <hi>Strand.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               <hi>DE Jure Uniformitatis Eccleſiaſticae,</hi> or Three Books of the Rights belonging to an Uniformity in Churches: In which things, the Laws of Nature, and Nations, and of the Divine Law concerning the Eccleſiaſtical State with the Civil, are unfolded. By <hi>Richard Davis,</hi> Chap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lain to His Grace the Duke of <hi>Buckingham,</hi> in <hi>Fol.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>The true Prophecies of</hi> Michael Noſtradamus, Phyſitian to <hi>Henry</hi> the Second, <hi>Francis</hi> the Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cond, and <hi>Charles</hi> the Ninth, Kings of <hi>France.</hi> and one of the beſt Aſtronomers that ever were. A work full of curioſity and learning. Tranſla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted by <hi>Theo. de Garencieres,</hi> Doctor of Phyſick, <hi>London. Folio.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Aerius Redivivus:</hi> Or the Hiſtory of the Preſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>byterians, containing the Beginning, Progreſs, and Succeſſes of that active Sect. Their oppoſiti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons to Monarchical and Epiſcopal Government, their Innovations in the Church, and their Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>broilments of the Kingdoms, and Eſtates of Chri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtendom, in the purſuit of their deſigns from the year 1536. to the year 1647. By <hi>Peter Heylin,</hi>
               <pb facs="tcp:51789:81"/>
D. D. And Chaplain to <hi>Charles</hi> the Firſt and Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cond Monarchs of <hi>Great Britain.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>The Compleat Horſeman, and Expert Farrier,</hi> in Two B<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>oks. 1. Shewing the manner of breed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing good Horſes, with their choice Nature, Ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding and Dieting, as well for Running as Hunt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing; as alſo directing the Groom, and Keeper, his true Office. 2. Directing the moſt exact and approved manner, how to know, and cure, all Diſeaſes in Horſes. A work containing the Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>crets and beſt skill belonging, either to Farrier, or Horſe-Leach; the Cures placed Alphabetical<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly; with hundreds of Medicines never before im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>printed by any Author. In <hi>Quarto.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>The famous Conclave, wherein</hi> Clement <hi>the Eight was elected Pope;</hi> with the Intrigues and Cunning Devices of that Eccleſiaſtical Aſſembly, in <hi>Quarto.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>A Familiar Diſcourſe between</hi> George <hi>a true hearted Engliſh Gentleman, and</hi> Hans <hi>a Dutch Merchant,</hi> concerning the preſent Affairs of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> in <hi>Quarto.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>A Short and Strange Relation of ſome part of the Life of</hi> Taffaletta, <hi>The Great Conqueror and Emperor of</hi> Barbary, in <hi>Quarto.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Paul Feſteau</hi>'s French Grammar, being the neweſt and exacteſt Method now extant, for the attaining to the Purity of the French Tongue. Augmented and inriched with ſeveral choice and new Dialogues in <hi>Octav<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>ΠΑΝΣΕΙΒΕΙΑ. Or a View of all Religi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons in the World, with the ſeveral Church Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernments from the Creation, to theſe times; al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſo a diſcovery of all known Hereſies in all Ages,
<pb facs="tcp:51789:81"/>
and Places, and choice Obſervations and Reflecti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons throughout the whole World. Enlarged and Perfected by <hi>Alexander Roſs,</hi> in <hi>Octavo.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Of Credulity and Incredulity in things Divine and Spiritual,</hi> (among other things) a true and faithful Account is given of the Platonick Philoſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phy, as it hath reference to Chriſtianity: As alſo the buſineſs of Witches, and Witchcraft, fully argued and diſputed by <hi>Merick Cauſabon,</hi> Doctor in Divinity, and one of the Prebends of <hi>Chriſt Church</hi> in <hi>Canterbury,</hi> in <hi>Octavo.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>The French Rogue,</hi> being a pleaſant Hiſtory of his life and fortune; adorned with variety of other Adventures of no leſs rarity: with Epigrams ſuit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able to each Stratagem, in <hi>Octavo.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Cicero</hi> againſt <hi>Cataline,</hi> in four Invective Ora<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions, containing the whole manner of diſcovering that notorious Conſpiracy, in <hi>Octavo.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Sermon Preche Devant le Roy à Whitehal. Par le Docteur Tillotſon, Doyen de Canterbury.</hi> In <hi>Octavo.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Sinners Tears, in Meditations, and Pray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers. By <hi>Tho Fettiplace, Dom. Pet. Cantab.</hi> In Twelves.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>The Gentile Sinner, or</hi> England's <hi>Brave Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tleman Charactered.</hi> In a Letter to a Friend, as he is, and as he ſhould be. By <hi>Clement Ellis, M. A.</hi> Fellow of <hi>Qu. Col. Oxon.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Idea Eloquentiae, ſive ut vulgo vocant Rhe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>toricae. De Periodis, Tropis, Figuris Verbo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rum, Figuris Senten<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>iarum, &amp; integrae Ora<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tionis partibus methodicè differens. Ac inſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per docens uſum tum Periodos, tum Figuras tum denique integram Orationem, juxta Artis Ora<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>toriae
<pb facs="tcp:51789:82"/>
regulas componendi. Authore</hi> Joanne de Kerhuel. S. E. M. <hi>in Octavo.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Cambridge Jeſts,</hi> &amp;c. in <hi>Duo decimo.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Private Devotions, digeſted into ſix Letanies.</hi> 1. Confeſſion. 2. Deprecation. 3. Supplication. 4. Thankſgiving. 5. Interceſſion. 6. For the Sick. With Directions and Prayers for the Lords day, Sacrament Day of Death and Judgment; and two daily Prayers for Morning and Evening. Twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty fours.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:51789:82"/>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
